{"qu1":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>1 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">Find the sum of the first 20 terms of an arithmetic progression, if its fifth term is 11 and its 16<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> term is 39. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>450\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>600\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>400\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>500\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu2":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>1 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">If <i>f <\/i>(<i>x<\/i>) = (<i>x <\/i>+ 2)<em><sup>x<\/sup><\/em> <sup>&minus;<\/sup> <sup>1<\/sup> (<i>x <\/i>+ 1)<em><sup>x<\/sup><\/em>, find the value of <i>f <\/i>(0) + <i>f <\/i>(1) + <i>f <\/i>(2). <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>36 <img Width='11' Height= '33' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAhCAYAAAAPm1F2AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIsSURBVDhPzdRLbxJRFAdwUlkiCtqghkV9JCS1Rls+QCmu1E2FxGeApC5Gv4E0aio1inWhJhaWvgZBqqgtZUd3hIfhA9SEECxhQQmkOiEwkPwdDtcJY0fWPclJOOf8knvv5F40GIhWq4VAYBkcx1EGg0GIosimgAJfungBWq0WTqdTSgc0Gg2u37jJpgP40aKPhu\/e86wDPPX7qRcIBKmW8cdIBB6PB51Oh3WAQqFAmOPuUK3Yxr8RWH5FeGXlE9X\/xdlMBvtGRjA9bZNXU8WZdJrg2XOTaDQarKuCP4R4Wnp29jJ2dn6xbj8U2P\/kMcF79x+wjjJkvJFMEnQ4nKhWq9ja+olisUhZq9XIyNg6NUlYLefmbpGR8erqN0SjUYTDYYRCIUXmct\/J7DrgsNgruFQqIZFIIB6PD82e0USk2+Z2u+FyuYZmz+zlr9FsNtkvZShwLPYZp8fHodPpYDabsbT0DN1ul00HcHxtjS7NlNVK9+G29FfQqxcWHjIxgK9dvQK9\/gAEQWAd4MzEBHT79fK2ZNx7PpVKhVX9OD42hiNHj6HdblO964D1eh08z8PpcNBKyeQGm6jgXDYLi8UCg8GAg1LG19fZRAX\/Pb0g\/IZ9ZoYOmc\/nqSdjUWwrnn0vspk04ecvXlIt4\/N2O06cPMWqfnz9EiP8+s1bqmU8771LA693HuVyGalUCoeMRhweHZVe+zYZxZ4XfT4YJWAymeiANpsNm5s\/2BT4A+EguFStjQ++AAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>37 <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAgCAYAAADEx4LTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHHSURBVDhP1ZRNSwJRGIWnUlwk1mgZunEhGfUPKnCbiS2qbUVlYF+7alviDyj7WBVUCzcGFVQrl1mi1qoEtxqkZmKGaAni6c71NliptKwDl5nznmeYmXfeOxxq6OL8DDabDfl8nlWAqvDt7Q061GooFC2sUtYXOB6PYWFhHhzHQSaTgeeVeHnJsPQb7NxYh1Qqxe7uHmasVjQ0NNaGY7FHpFIpej5jnaZ3qAlXanpq8t\/BE+Njv4cXSb95nkcm88oqdeBcLod0Oo1SqcQqdeBq+iuwy+WC2WyGyWSquwSGSyaTiEQiiEajdZfA\/MVuBPx+DFks0Ov16Ovvh9t9xJKyRNjn89EtpdFo4XA4SAcG6CBtb+8wogIeHRmmYTyRYBWgy2CAqq0db+\/v1IvwA2lPKBRirqwuQydayQ7\/AX8qm83C4\/FgbnYWzXI5jk9OWVIFDgT80Ol0kEokUKnacOn1sqQKXCgUUCwW8Uy+bF9vL5rIRXd39zQTYWHIhYGvlO\/6ir60c3OLehEeJK3q7u5hrizh5yjA+weH1IvwyvISDVbX7EiQ9gWDAajV7VAqVcQ\/UebLM9vtayRUQqvV0qPRaEQ4HGYp8AGOxbiPWrNZpwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>37 <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAfCAYAAAAx6zerAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIrSURBVDhPzZTfT1JhGMfB0tiYpYYy0UnFlnd4A9XYYNW4hK5CuMglNsal3uSqPyD\/A0mlLUnJqyzaKrvJO9ngAthUUNtk4YQhG1f8kODbOQ8vv+rAXVvf7d3Z9\/l+3rP3Oec5R4QmZbNZLCy8hNPpxOzcHPb291lSVR2ulMu4f+8u+vsH4HA4oNVqMDI6inAkwogm+MXzZxCJRNjZ8ZM\/Py9CdnUAt27fIc+rDseiUWxtfWOuqmtjY7h+Q4VKpUK+5cy8CoUC\/H4\/5ueforf3Mny+TywRgCPhMJRKJcRiMRSKEezu7rFEAC4Wi3T3k5MEJtRqXOnrw89EgrI6XCqVkMlkmKvq65fP1PSHjz7ydXjGPg25XE6banrtXiH4+\/Y2+TrsWX1DwaOpKYRCIWxuvseFri6o1RPI5\/PEtJzZtbiIoaFBSCQSWmbzAxwfx1kq0CDfXDweRyqVYpWG\/oI76R\/C6XQawWAQgUCg4+IZkdfrhc1mg9Vq7bh45n9pkF0FleCmrXlW2sL26cf0yg8OD1mlDbyyvExDxa9oLMaqAnCYmzge0mo09LXEYgcs+QPO5XJQDA\/DPvMEbz2rtKktPGl5CJlsEGXua3azowjCr1wu9PRcwtHRD\/I1OJlsjCrBv7jHwwcXu7thNplgNBoxfnOcajqdDu82NlrhSYsFJg40GAzQ6\/VQqVQEa7hG19bXG7CQ3EtLBJ+eJlmlA7zm8UAqleLsrPZ7AH4DxmZz95ni4LEAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>38 <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAgCAYAAADEx4LTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAGTSURBVDhP1dTNSgJRGAbg8QddiAzVwi6hugLbSrqemrb9aSYaaGBuqqVZQWqbbGUXYJs0na5ABMEWbk0X2sKNTCYIgvI2czwMTjji0j74YM57HmbOGc4MA43Kv+Xg8\/nQ7\/dpAkzFH5UKVm02WK0sTcalwu12G6FgEAzDwGQyYWl5BaL4TWf\/4IdkAnq9Ho+pFDxuN3Q6vTb+arXI3eXyHnvIEzTxZLmPDv8dPtjfmx\/7Trwwm83z4U6ng2azidFoRJMZeFotCs5kMuB5HhzHzWzZMI1GA+Vyea5exLchiiKi0SgcDgfp61gMP70enZ3AMtxYXyOHR9452b10bbdvotvtEqPgq8sLMvmazdIEeJK+RTmLJ5JkrGBBKCASiWA4HNIE+KzVCPb7T8l45gbvbm8IzucLZKyJ3wWBQG57hyYaOCetW4ZOpwuDwYCmU3A8fj9eZyCgWr9cKnwWGv+60ulnmqhLwS\/S6ZMhz++iWq2iVCqhWCySrtfrxCjY5dyCxWIBy7IwGo0wGAxKh8PnkgB+ASmet1zYl\/TwAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu3":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>1 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">The amount of profit made on an article is twice the amount of discount offered on it. If the percentage of discount offered on the article is 12.5%, by what percentage was the cost price of the article marked up before offering the discount? <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>53 <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAgCAYAAADEx4LTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHHSURBVDhP1ZRNSwJRGIWnUlwk1mgZunEhGfUPKnCbiS2qbUVlYF+7alviDyj7WBVUCzcGFVQrl1mi1qoEtxqkZmKGaAni6c71NliptKwDl5nznmeYmXfeOxxq6OL8DDabDfl8nlWAqvDt7Q061GooFC2sUtYXOB6PYWFhHhzHQSaTgeeVeHnJsPQb7NxYh1Qqxe7uHmasVjQ0NNaGY7FHpFIpej5jnaZ3qAlXanpq8t\/BE+Njv4cXSb95nkcm88oqdeBcLod0Oo1SqcQqdeBq+iuwy+WC2WyGyWSquwSGSyaTiEQiiEajdZfA\/MVuBPx+DFks0Ov16Ovvh9t9xJKyRNjn89EtpdFo4XA4SAcG6CBtb+8wogIeHRmmYTyRYBWgy2CAqq0db+\/v1IvwA2lPKBRirqwuQydayQ7\/AX8qm83C4\/FgbnYWzXI5jk9OWVIFDgT80Ol0kEokUKnacOn1sqQKXCgUUCwW8Uy+bF9vL5rIRXd39zQTYWHIhYGvlO\/6ir60c3OLehEeJK3q7u5hrizh5yjA+weH1IvwyvISDVbX7EiQ9gWDAajV7VAqVcQ\/UebLM9vtayRUQqvV0qPRaEQ4HGYp8AGOxbiPWrNZpwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>40%\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>50%\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>60%\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu4":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>1 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">In the figure given below, ABCD and PQRS are identical squares, each of side 2 units. Find the area (in sq. units) of the shaded region, if PC = PD. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhmQDEAPcAAP\/\/\/wAAAMPDw93d3aenp2lpaSMjI4mJiUdHRzAwMNHR0ejo6CEhISUlJSgoKN\/f38\/Pzw0NDQgICLW1teDg4C4uLiQkJNjY2O\/v7woKCgYGBioqKgsLC39\/f2BgYBUVFQICAgQEBPf390BAQLe3t1BQUDg4ONfX1wAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAmQDEAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzhnBti5U0DOnyADDBBIIMDNAgaAfhQ60KhNAwZ8KuXIFICAAjYJHDiAdepGnjsR2EQwYIBTrxmrAgggVaYAsQAQEECbdqhAuTQLgE1K96JatTHPrm3bdyLYAHNnaiVYoGvhxwoN2BVodnKCw5gza97MubNnzwkgNxW9UPBj06QLou67OrXA1mhhp5Y9lbZo20Bxn57tGqHunL9Z8+5tMPhN47GHEyeIvGbz2sqXv44u\/blO6cypL7cuk\/tP7zDB4\/8U75K8TfMs0dNUr5J9d+3E3aOUHx5+b\/om8Ze371o\/Sf9NgeVYUPx5pJYBiRFIGoCvTVbAASIxGJKEBxJmYIEdHQZhhBhSNdl\/HX714UgSKlgSYCSGqBGKHC6I3WguvriWioWVuJSMM8ZYkgILnGTjhSUJwEADPZ5Io0UCOPAABBEUmaKOIQkgwQOvEQkilB8leVYAEFjZ4m0iJfnAlgB06eSNWHIkZo45MnlmhkdCJCWVbG7pJZBgeqQljHWaiWaeaipJ5nTT+QlnmhetOWidArl5KKAZzUkoo5MGcGdacSq0Z6V8bmkopohOJOaipI72qV+ZHqRop6wS6ihGPz4fWpGklNZK6qUUxUpVog6Uyumva51qWKoDjdqqrawKG\/+Rrl\/NqiSywPr66rChMkSrr9DaiutDzK440QS9HovtuF1SQC2kDk1QwZjithttmRZcIFG3oD6kLgbZjuvuAxnICxG9sEI0gQb45utuvhv46xDAqKZbgb7vRlznAwlzq+K9EBsssVEUK1xaiPdqLDLE\/HqcEMMW2TZwwRm3fHAAFX9crUDqurzxy011LDO6BWGM881Az6jzyfyFbPPIP5dMdKgrB3300zEXR1BRO22o1Go1\/4y00zlHnZ1AB\/AFgAFWlwdWgnwO5DPXbCM99NdrTWZWYJMhplrPFeD7tNZ7A6D0128dNxkBcKXd9NaI972W104RLjjck2bdtuJPv+3\/VODnfWiaU2snzvfn0w29pdwstkf63UaD7vnkAil9VtgDGTBgS2o5ztzhlKtOecKCHcBT2eXVbWEAHATQwfHGI398B8kzv3zz0D8vvfLUO1999NdPz7wHH6B8MlgWPgDCZ+SXb\/75h4UgAmQPjEDniySUsH5f7b8vY\/zze1U\/jgThr7\/7\/CuI\/4CyvwAKUH4\/KaABD5i\/mihwgQy0yQMhGMGZTJCCFYTJBTGYwZZskIMdVMkHQRhCsPFkdhsZIQlDiJSBIKBwKQTgCh0yQADMjSAIWtZOxEYQFc7QIAMkwOy4ApGogA2GfpPhDx\/iPyJODYUJuWGDejgCCCwRIhgw\/8EJACDEgjjRIQZgS0IwUMUrNoSMVrShUwYAIbxAxHc7QdtA0GhGhdBxIC0cAAICwMOICECMBrljHQsiyIFQDTEBQKJCbHcXOc6xjIN8ZBqpkpjKjBGSgywkVXgyokBi8oqabEkoSThKUX6SlKeMSSkXuMqXtBJHr3RlKgMYS5jUsje3tOUssZNLVe6SOL2USTDRMkxh\/lI0xZxJMnGyTGUeky7NpEk0fTlJXD4TKNO0STZXsk1tXtOb1XxRN0syTmZ+k5oULOdH1PkTdm7Ene08p0rgiU15noSeSsFnRPSZT3uKhJ9TAagd\/WlAgR7EoF5BqCQjSUiCYkSh0HRoRQkg2heAUrQw+ry\/6GPoqVHIuLOjyJToQMPJ0DOK9KAnzWRKF1pSikwTpNJpJkx5KdGZvkgEJSCBRCAwgoK1VCM41elDeOrTnwI1pw4hqlE9ElSGKHWpTEVqQp4K1agK1SBUrapVsdpTrYqkqQPJqlc\/AlaxjpWsOTXrWdHa1bWWRARFdatc50rXuq5oL3bN0GQQALy8pmxwivRrrvbaV8EaBiyBNey8hlIUxdZFIC107F+bUljJLmxwgLSsZjfL2c569rOgDe1mAwIAOw==\" style=\"width: 153px; height: 196px;\" \/><br \/>\r\n\t<\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>1\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAfCAYAAAAx6zerAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIrSURBVDhPzZTfT1JhGMfB0tiYpYYy0UnFlnd4A9XYYNW4hK5CuMglNsal3uSqPyD\/A0mlLUnJqyzaKrvJO9ngAthUUNtk4YQhG1f8kODbOQ8vv+rAXVvf7d3Z9\/l+3rP3Oec5R4QmZbNZLCy8hNPpxOzcHPb291lSVR2ulMu4f+8u+vsH4HA4oNVqMDI6inAkwogm+MXzZxCJRNjZ8ZM\/Py9CdnUAt27fIc+rDseiUWxtfWOuqmtjY7h+Q4VKpUK+5cy8CoUC\/H4\/5ueforf3Mny+TywRgCPhMJRKJcRiMRSKEezu7rFEAC4Wi3T3k5MEJtRqXOnrw89EgrI6XCqVkMlkmKvq65fP1PSHjz7ydXjGPg25XE6banrtXiH4+\/Y2+TrsWX1DwaOpKYRCIWxuvseFri6o1RPI5\/PEtJzZtbiIoaFBSCQSWmbzAxwfx1kq0CDfXDweRyqVYpWG\/oI76R\/C6XQawWAQgUCg4+IZkdfrhc1mg9Vq7bh45n9pkF0FleCmrXlW2sL26cf0yg8OD1mlDbyyvExDxa9oLMaqAnCYmzge0mo09LXEYgcs+QPO5XJQDA\/DPvMEbz2rtKktPGl5CJlsEGXua3azowjCr1wu9PRcwtHRD\/I1OJlsjCrBv7jHwwcXu7thNplgNBoxfnOcajqdDu82NlrhSYsFJg40GAzQ6\/VQqVQEa7hG19bXG7CQ3EtLBJ+eJlmlA7zm8UAqleLsrPZ7AH4DxmZz95ni4LEAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAgCAYAAADEx4LTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAGTSURBVDhP1dTNSgJRGAbg8QddiAzVwi6hugLbSrqemrb9aSYaaGBuqqVZQWqbbGUXYJs0na5ABMEWbk0X2sKNTCYIgvI2czwMTjji0j74YM57HmbOGc4MA43Kv+Xg8\/nQ7\/dpAkzFH5UKVm02WK0sTcalwu12G6FgEAzDwGQyYWl5BaL4TWf\/4IdkAnq9Ho+pFDxuN3Q6vTb+arXI3eXyHnvIEzTxZLmPDv8dPtjfmx\/7Trwwm83z4U6ng2azidFoRJMZeFotCs5kMuB5HhzHzWzZMI1GA+Vyea5exLchiiKi0SgcDgfp61gMP70enZ3AMtxYXyOHR9452b10bbdvotvtEqPgq8sLMvmazdIEeJK+RTmLJ5JkrGBBKCASiWA4HNIE+KzVCPb7T8l45gbvbm8IzucLZKyJ3wWBQG57hyYaOCetW4ZOpwuDwYCmU3A8fj9eZyCgWr9cKnwWGv+60ulnmqhLwS\/S6ZMhz++iWq2iVCqhWCySrtfrxCjY5dyCxWIBy7IwGo0wGAxKh8PnkgB+ASmet1zYl\/TwAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAgCAYAAADEx4LTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIySURBVDhPzZRfaFJxFMdFtA188E28LGRB9eqC1Xoqsy2oHoaGPSrSwAmNRtlztcEKbIvadGZbj2VM+2NK9bBYkIbuTXsxlmxkyHqYgn9WzvXt3uNvF2036XFfOHC\/53x+3HN\/3HNkaNKP9XWMj43B4XDgyugo0unPrNKQCJfLZfT1HYNarYbVakWPXg8txyEe\/8SIJviixQKZTIbk8jL5arUKjtPi4KHDqG1tUU6EPywtIRB4xlxDR3r0UO7rQIU\/KKilZ0H1eh35fB5zc4\/Q2dGJidt3WEUCTiYT0Gg01JJWy2F1dY1VJOBCoYBMJoNYLIYD3d3o6tqPb7kc1XbBzYpGXtMbvLM+8iI8MnIZJpOZuYbisY\/SsGlwkAoLC0HyhY0NHOfvXS6X8219oZwIF4tFnDIY6IBOp4NKpYJSqcT8\/GNGSPQcjUbhdrvh9\/uRy31n2YbafuDf2itwOByG3W6HzWZrGwIjS6VSiEQi\/xV78TZ+bm7C4\/HAwo+YEF7vLH7VaqzaBJdKJRzt7aV\/w2g0UgjPp\/sHUKlUiBHhWzdvUPHJ0wDLAFOTdyk3PTNDXoSfh0JwOp00gzv6urJC8PCwk3zbD7w3NUnwi5evyP8Tfr+4SODZc+exvf2bcpLwu7dvCDxx0kDLZke74OkH9wm8NDSEWtO1CWqBXdeuEujzPWSZVolwKBgk0Gy+wG\/PNBKJBL8U4xTZbJYYET4z0E9DKmxRYVAVCoUYLtd1ngD+AGC8kkN1gNFpAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu5":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>1 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">If&nbsp; <img src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAIEAAAAPCAYAAADDGqz4AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAmeSURBVFhH5VkHUFZXFgZcitKUroglRqQIithBBwuJiEoWjbpxN4YuCir+dNSQKBqdMdZYIolGiIodVNSNiAVQyFpHjTV2ERULPyjWs+ecd9\/PD\/4obgzjbL6ZN9xzzv3vve+977SHVnp6OkRFTYKKigqob6zLyICwsDB48OCB0NQf5s2bC5MmKeDly5dC89fBz+lpMGXql0IC0Bo1ahSYmZkLsX6RGB8PWlpa8LiyUmjqDwN9BoC5pZWQ\/jo4ceI4WJibQ\/fuPYUGSUCe2KSJGZTeuydU9YeoCROYBDdu3hSa+oN3\/35gZm4BL168EJr\/bzx8+BBmzpzBz5suD49ewqJGgrulpax49uwZTJ8+Hdzc3MDZ2RnGjAmH8+fPs01GZuYW6NXLk+2JSUmwYsUKUCgUoCwvFzPqBpkE12\/cEBqA2bNngbu7O68dFBwMp0\/\/JiwSsrO3g5eXF9sV0dGwatUqDOuT4P79+2JG3VCTBMqyMoiPiwMXFxfV2jfUzkX4GVNnt65d2f7NrFmwZPFiSEqaDM+fPxcz3g75eXkQGRkJRUW\/Cg1AOobqkJAQuHjxd6F5Nxj9+b\/4WcfGxoGzkxN06OAmLGokeIBMIQL4DRnCk4ePGAFxcbGgp6sLJiamcOToUf7BsiVL2N69Rw+IiYkBKysrlum6VVLCc+oKmQTFt0o4N48cOYJlf39\/SMBUYdioERgYNISCgwd5fnpaGtvdOnXCm4kFW1tb1d6Xr1zhOXWFTALaV6ksA4+ePXmdgIBAUCCpaGzbvDlcunSZ50+dMoV1Awb4MOlMTExYNjY2gadPn\/Kct8WFC+d5jZ7CK7dv28by0KHD3nmNlr09G44dO87j9s5O4NzehccEFQle4MPYgV5Gh\/hm1mxhBjh16hTrBvoOYsYbGxlCh45VLCq9excsLS1AT98ASm7fZt1t\/Dtz5kwIDQ2FadOmIasvsr4mZBJUVDyCvAP7eTx5ylRhBfgdf6evpweevXqzx9pYW4F9u3aqYk6pVEILOzvQ0dGBK1evso7Om5iQwHtnZmayThNkEhCWLlnMe\/+0Ko1lwv59e1k3duw4KMcIR+MBPj7CKp1ND89ma2unkQRbtmyBI0eOCKl2xEQreO3Vq9eAgb4eRtjewqIZOTk5sGjRolqv23fuiJm1w9GhHbR3cRWSGgkIkePG8oHk1CCDHphp4yaQn5\/P9gULFwmLBDnUKJXlUIz5vWWLFix369aN\/zbG357+rXpYJ8gkeIoRaHJiAo+vXbsurBKG+v8ddHX14SBGA7KnpMwQFgnjI8ax\/j52GLm5e5AQ2mBtYwOdMFqQPiJyvMYOgO7J3MKSx4MH+YKRsfEr9YGToyM4ObeH3b\/8wmtt2rxFWCT07eMFJqaNXyGB7NHjIiKFpnY8fPgA7O3b8vy29u04d78OGWvXQjSmqtqu69erPz9NeC0JggID+DDlNULR2PAx0KDB39izyJ76w4\/CIiFqovQyCTHRUij9z+HDLFM1SnJgUDDL6lAngSJqIo\/vYGRRR2JCHOu3bt3Kf+fOnScsEqZOmcx6IuDwT4ehZzaHx4+lbmMG1jZk05Qq1EnQv19fsNDQKQz2Hcievn79Ol4nO3uHsEgYNtQfyVM9HZATULSk+fEJiUL7enj07MHzN2zYKDR\/Ll5LgrjYGD7M1Rre2KWzO3pXUzhxXHqh0TFxwiKBHqKWljbnsX\/v2gVz5nwrLBLsmtvCx5hLa0KdBDNSpBd25uxZYZVA3mZkZAwnT55kexgWqurw\/8SP9VRc3scOh1KRjMlJiRhF9KC4+JbQVEGdBCOHD+fao+LRI5Zl2GFN4N65iyoK1YyAjo4OYG5uWY0EXbt2gT59+2I0tIPxEyYKbe1QTIritQ0MDMDb+yOhrR0L5s8HPz+\/Wq\/aUq86iAQaa4JnmO9\/LSrkAwWpee2mjRtZFxAYxHKP7hjitbWhoKAAMM7C2jVr2E4eoakw3L5N8uC0tHShqYJMgrIyJZwWtcfIkf+gZRk7d+xg3dBhn7L8sbc3y3tyc1nOwshE9QC9aLkmIPyQuhwcsHagud8vTxXa6lCvCTZv2sRzE7HSlyHXCcnJX+F5XsAHrVuDKYb+k3hOShv0MsjesmVrFQmmff0Vv0yqjVohCd6UDuZ+O4fXWLrse\/hu0UIe79u3X1g1g17yoUOHar2ofnkTiASuHTry3CsYJZkE5MXyd4IkkZtb4U17eEgVM1XjxcXFbL986RK0\/fBD1ltZWmKaaIDhzwgaGRqpCkMZx48dxcJOl4srTQjDVojWkVvEFBG+7bDY8\/T05LGTk7PqBVOobY\/tGe+NXQntbYK5nEigHvIpJycnJ6OnOmJt4K6x3ererSto6zTgeoFeakhwEK9Lv5FrmT59+yFBy3j+YUxvNjbWrLewsAAd3Ju6l2aYfghH0E62A3n5LFtamGObGcNjTVgiSPbZZ\/9k+RFGoYYNDcDB0QmeaCg03yWaNcWayb0zrMTWXksbu6uioiLMRRug8skTMQU9cOdOfHHh2C4FwMqVP8ETYaPu4B6SpbKyEjZv3gzLly+H8xcuQG9PDy4cSS8jK0uqH4JDQoXmVdCDXb16NT8AGTk5uyEiIoL3Tk1NVdnoRZWW3uOzZGVl8d5nzpyFQZi3OZRraKlKbt3iM4wdFyE0VdizJ4dzsHrRuBGjXkhwMAQGBsK6detVNtqTyFCBnpORkcF7X7t2Ddqgo7i6duT7bo7tqourK+zevRu2IQlNTYxh0OAhcKiwkNeoCaoz6N7VUVCQj8975Z\/+CX8bRmfqMqiI9PTwAKmaqyPocBZmZvD56C+EBuDmzRscCXr19hIagIULpFA5f8FCofnjoJBLOZp6aBn3SrE9Ra\/s1Kkzy\/SCMjOzeCyjsakp+GJ7+0dAUbARen1cXLzQVLXORPJybFWtMTI1bdoU6xcjMDQ0BG1Mmbq6ujB4iJ\/4xfuHc+fOgoODw9uRgJCYIH3vb4c519fXF0OyDufKwsIitu\/atZPt8dirkxffwb61BGuFN7U+dcGMlBReu02bNry3vr4+htBGcOBAHtud8Ia0tXXYSwnLlkoftmp2M\/8LAr4YzWt1wFzq4+PDY+pEzp2TvqaWlyv5uwVFDLrMmjSG0NCwalHufcPevbmwZs3atycBIS8vD6IVCggPD4fvFi+GR48fCwvAR9792Wvs7e35i16zZs34os+V7wJFGF5jsYuhvefPX6DK2QSpZnACa2sb\/uxNJKH\/FL4rUOczAYtZ2nsFhu3X4YPWrWDql8lCep8B8F\/pwP9rS8YajgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align: middle; width: 120px; height: 14px;\" \/>&nbsp; find the number of digits in <i>x<\/i>. [log 2 = 0.3010] <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>4\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>5\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>6\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>7\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu6":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>1 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9999999;\">The units digit of the number (2468)<sup>1<\/sup><sup>3<\/sup><sup>5<\/sup><sup>7<\/sup> is <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>2.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>8.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>4.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>6.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu7":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>7<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\">If <em>x<\/em><sup>2<\/sup> + <em>y<\/em><sup>2<\/sup> = 2<em>x<\/em> + 4<em>y<\/em> + 4, find the maximum possible value of 4<em>x<\/em> + 3<em>y<\/em>, for real values of <i>x <\/i>and <i>y<\/i>. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"25","CORRECT_ANSWER":"25","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu8":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>14<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">The total discount offered through two successive discounts of 20% and 25% is equivalent to a single discount of <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>22.5%.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>40%.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>45%.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>50%.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu9":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>14<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices.<\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhYgEmAPcAAP\/\/\/87OzhMTEwAAALOzs15eXvPz80NDQzU1Nebm5oyMjCIiIiYmJlZWVoKCgkhISJycnMLCwkRERGVlZSMjI8PDw93d3VdXV0dHR2lpaaenp4mJiQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAYgEmAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bGAAIGDCAgkUCBigYO8HwZAEEClgWGWlSgc8CCozZl+lSYNOrABAgCAAjAQCtEBUolMg27koBTqCmxerVY1SpNsAnVmiyg84CBh1MFtnVooIEDnT8hBniAgCxDugMUZCwgAIJRlHQbP7bYd61bmH3\/DggMILLjo0w3g1QQuIBiiXIfJljwc7XhhH0jCIVYoLUEtBeL4h6pwO5quxdXN319GeXq1gt49jbw28DyoMQ3mpYY9DRe4AAUWGeoHfpD3R7Bl\/9MXRsjV62Vi7ckgF07+QKp83ZErDM6wtXbHcLVmz9hgAYGeOcQe3d1JB5JBPI3n33qibRfZ2BhZ5pZTYnWUYKpOYQTgwcJmOFCoTXVH0LycXTgSAkKKB2HDXrkYVYpCpVgSAkW8NR3ArBo0HF6cfaQigzpVt1GJ4p0XmcCWEZRihPs1iJJPHb205GMBSAXAUlGREEFAFSgkwUHIXbBZA2FWB9epgE2EZDc6TRiRUViZMEACIV2AYAZhZblQnMOgEEGfNJJ0JYAYKDBRhpgkBEGAwBqkE+hcWYnnhTeqCWXGzj65KYfzWlVog55OiiXhiKqKEYDgOnSlhvodCqnsCr\/xKhOAmEw66leNipoTRroREGmhd4qUK4Z7FqoThX86apAfRoLQAaHdkkBAL3qdCiopRZ6aLMGNQtmU1y2RCiwEuXa1AYlFVuhqiep2xS7FpH7Z6HTAjAAl6k+6+xEFFRYL0agAotBvffaC2axBRE6sEAFF6zBv12emsEGovZKraLZluowxPZy+TDD8K40rqaxlpyQwNEaCioAotoUMKAZa7ByywIpnLLMrxI6EAVg8kyQp9jevDIAOke8M74hqzSyyUwXZC7MN5Nr76eKolyrBlI7a\/PV1YJL0MTJ7tzUxdpyXWHBAg2NAdIvLW3Q2RUOZK5O6DIM974I3U2rQO5+\/zmQ3ngXBDhCfecr+N0LZVCv1drOjPfgB\/XbFMd2w73Qy2U3firNRJMq9KsGJTtxlwUDrSi0XINOUNg1s\/024LDvDZHbTTNd6pxQX92xvlQDwLjGXCI8aubAs2y42GCuzCjZGQA656GlH7\/7xwa3jSnJJhVtUgWUs6S9uR\/HTLquMXFfEObiE+tssYnebDyyBmWQs7X3ruwr6s2GO5C3IIdHpkYlwotOLEUQDeiPI5VyEvYQshc45WQnBjFgi3BypoIssHYYfNB3HkMag6juJhz0EcsuWJAPTUQuRyLIB62Cwq78jIQYNFlm1CSROC0EMW8K0v9uOADJOCki8mkgSfYihZEg6iiGFEGMhNw0HtYAwDViEeFhbPND7kgxIctpzkZM6CC7sMkiXESiRjoIISk98TYIak8OD4KTPWloh4IRgBsX8p6NDMkk8bnimg6wRjFqxDQ2DMmDphORMJIIOxUxZEFmREiM4AclFGqKHgu5gD76sSL02cmMSvIiJTlEiAoJYBJZFKMjKmRDKdlkRlB5SY9gCEaT\/EiUyjMg4CjSIELiI0Re6Uk2urBK5smRSq40x4mwspUXAo6NEpBLSxYxTRZ6iJ56qZDQOLMg05SmTu5UoKWczZQXSSBGzARBZP5xmxxkojnXyc52uvOd8IynPOdJz3ob2vOe+MynPvfJz376858ADahAB0rQghoUnwEBADs=\" style=\"width: 354px; height: 38px;\" \/><\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>45\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<p>\r\n\t108<\/p>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='19' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABMAAAAfCAYAAAAFkva3AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAK5SURBVEhL7ZVfSFNhGMY3u3EzExMd3uymqV15l5DdeOXMkG6s9QeVqNhGN5oi2p8bLfzXjQaGIdsKA926ya3EzMgJBoYOjBlsmegczou5uRtzQ5\/Oefe1ddrZMnZZD7xwvud99uM75z3fjgRM7W1t0Gq1ouVyuSgzMfFGtB8IBKgfg+l1OlRUVMRKrVYjK0sOiUSCtbV1yjTU10EulwtyVVVncXBA7Tjsd72bmiJQV1c3rSORCBQFBaiuPkdrMYnCdnaCOJ6bi9PlZ5gD+DY3Cd7a2gar1Qqz2czteI11oxKF6XVa+qFz+QtzgLeTk+RlZmZCoVDQ7fLrwcEnLCEC825sUEijucScqCzcTvLz89HT24e9vT0Eg0FoLl6g7NzcR8okwB4+6KTAwsIic+La399nV1G5uSnzWb3+Fq0FsANuLEWqEyguLmFOXF6vFw6Hg62i8njWCVZX30BrAWx19Rs1G5tuMyeuaw311HO5vzIHeDEyQt6Y2UJrAey1zUrN0dEx5sT1aX4eUq6nUhVheHgYj\/r6KFvOTTwcDlNGAHs\/PY3a2losLiY+L14zMx+grqxEYWEhlEolGhubEAqFWFdkAOnoX4E5nU6YTCYYDIa0ymg0QsIf2paWFjQ3N6dVPOP\/NKPyeDyw2WxU\/HUqpYR1dnTQeeT\/COVyGaTSDPT3D7BuopLCbOzQX79xE37\/Nrb9fpyvqSHPbp9lKaGSwp4ODaG0tJRAP\/V5aYlg7e13mCPUXw3g+TMTwSyWl8wR6tAwt9uF7OyjOFVWht3d78wV6lAw\/sjl5BxDSclJ+La2mJuoP8LGx1\/hSEYG1NyX288NIZVSwh4PDHCvgxR3791nTmolhc3a7fSw+R2trKxgmbvVJW6afPl8PpYSKins6pXL3Ndbhry8PHppZTJZrLp7elnqVwE\/AGKf4jJJGcZyAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\tCannot be determined<\/p>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu10":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>14<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<br ><span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'>How many integral values of <i>x <\/i>satisfy the inequality |3x \u2013 5| \u2264 15?\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>13\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>11\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>10\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>12\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu11":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>14<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">If the profit obtained from selling five apples is the same as the selling price of three apples, what is the profit percentage from selling one apple? <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>75%\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>100%\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>150%\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>175%\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu12":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>14<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">Find the smallest positive integer <i>n<\/i>, such that <em>n<\/em><sup>2<\/sup><sup>0<\/sup><sup>0<\/sup> &gt; 9<sup>3<\/sup><sup>0<\/sup><sup>0<\/sup>. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>24\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>27\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>31\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>28\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu13":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>14<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">If each of A, B and C, working independently, takes 9 days, 14 days and 14 days more respectively to complete a certain job when compared to the time taken by A, B and C working together, in how much time will B and C together complete the same job? <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>6 days\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>10 days\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>12 days\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>20 days\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu14":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>8 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>14<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">In the figure given below, ABC is a rightangled triangle, right angled at B. Find the measure of BD, if AB = 15, BC = 20 and BD is perpendicular to AC. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhlQB+APcAAP\/\/\/2lpaSMjI8PDw6enp4mJiUdHR93d3QAAAOfn539\/f\/f397+\/vxAQEEBAQN\/f38fHxzAwMK+vr+\/v71BQUHh4eIeHhzg4OCgoKLe3t0hISI+Pj3BwcM\/Pz9fX15eXl2hoaFhYWGBgYJ+fnx4eHiAgIJqami8vL5aWllRUVD8\/PycnJysrK01NTSIiIl9fXxcXF0NDQxgYGDc3N52dnWdnZxoaGtjY2JmZmSEhIVNTUwwMDAEBAcrKyioqKgAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAlQB+AAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypypMYAAmjhVChAwIKdPkgQKFAjwsyhIAwcOIDDKdOMAAwINEGhK1WIABFgR3KzKNeLSgQh6dh27MCjBAETJqj0o4ABBpW7Xyp1Lt65djAkULLhbl0EDBw\/4zmXgAEIECYLXEgYwgUKFxGQXC7RwIQFkrpIFQsCQ4TLVzAInaHjs2SjogRYcWC7t8\/RABhEYsM7pemACBwpm06xNUIFq3TF5E4QNAfhL4QQTXLBgvCXyghU0TGiu8nnBDBiKUz9pvaDyDdtNdv83yIHC9PAixxuUEEE7+o\/qDT5wAP5hVqxT3yOMb3BB+fMMIRAXAAjkp19B\/B0kwQUdNCTgQARAdSCCDmTkwQUfBDgggRNSqNECIIQA4EEPgtXhcBVuRACDCZUIgFInvpbiRhdmSOKAEcYoUIIMgSjCXgW5GJaOAPDY0AgYeBDkfWLpaCRDEpBQgglELvSkQg+cMAEKJaQAZJUGXYnQAipo18EKLCgJpocdcVBfaC24YOCaRc6o0Qgv9AdDDCB8CaaYBsng3kAiaADABxeo+aedFs6AAkE0uABkBxcgtqhHC9Twwl4d2HADQY1x4OeJgCI0wgkQuIDDQRsARmSpCHnHkIMOCRlmKamMcgSBA6MWFGqMsBo0QQSBMbRBZR0GWxAFtzK0WWcHKjvQBhxEJBpp70kLwK69NkTZauFJO2yxExkmW7i5XsTsRbfltp2y1GrkG7jABcvtRrCdW2+6E43bUbvGwbruRwpIp1up8YaE3aCXAXqvSMoxV5qY\/pYU3YiCiTmwSRm01zC\/DiWM0nxv8vXkwyn5Z17GIC9UMUvsMTxYywpt3NJ8NvZFM0IivwSiiDpLhHJMKzY4s7XE5lTj0RDZTNPP3f9+tjNBPftEQASKdqXe0D95EMEIkU3NWNJULSDCj1qL7XRTI2CN2dRVV3XhnKbtzDVXE4TQZ1PPLYABuWshmnVrNIsAdl2U0o0TciOIwFfeexOekNdRy\/WBq7Txu4DbkNmaOUKGlxZq5SvV1rhurQJ+XK6UA2cYtDCdtvngrF0bHKOhb\/ftcTvch1UE6D3rEgNfAUB58duJ5m7pX83OoX7zMi9Q7sijl291S50uUPXoAYwS8a1vH6NvGKeHAOfiA5udeDz4jsAODMQv\/\/z012\/\/\/fjnr\/\/+\/ONPQAMlC0kPXOCAAhrwgAhMoAIXyMAGOvCBEIzgAX2QlQLQ6SQF2ApiAARgwY34rkkXdBGMPBgXAnCvSk8RiZAuKJAchaREA0jLBVP4wvtIiIUidBFGhATCNWVwIAKQYUZcJBUWCqQAFeyIkDZkxI\/4TnFNjKIUp0jFKlrxiljMoha3yMUuerEkAQEAOw==\" style=\"width: 149px; height: 126px;\" \/><br \/>\r\n\t<\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>12.5\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>10\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>9\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>12\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu15":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>15 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>16<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">Ravi wrote two numbers, M and N, where M is a two-digit number, with non-zero digits, in base 8, while N is another two-digit number, also in base 8, obtained by reversing the order of the digits in M. If M<sup>2<\/sup> &minus; N<sup>2<\/sup> = P<sup>2<\/sup>, where P is a natural number, in base 10, find the sum of the digits of P.<\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"3","CORRECT_ANSWER":"3","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu16":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>15 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>16<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">How many integral values of <i>n <\/i>satisfy the equation 2<em>nx<\/em> &minus; 60 = 9<em>x<\/em>, where <i>x <\/i>is a natural number? <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"4","CORRECT_ANSWER":"4","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu17":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>17<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>Walking 20% faster than his normal speed, Raghu reaches his school four minutes early. Instead, if he walks 25% slower than his normal speed, in how much time (in minutes) will he reach his school?\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>27\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>28\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>30\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>32\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu18":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>18<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>Akash said to Akansha, when I will be four times your present age, you will be three times my present age. If Akash is four years older than Akansha, find the sum of their present ages (in years).\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"36","CORRECT_ANSWER":"36","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu19":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>19<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:;size:9999999\">If <i>p <\/i>&oplus; <i>q <\/i>= <img height=\"40\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAHQAAAAoCAYAAAAv1t6rAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAArHSURBVHhe7ZsLWI3ZGsczUzgnukoZFeM+0001D2pOZZhBhpLQTAwRlRhkQhLOM48JGck1lyJhKOTSRTHnnCkzbmMwo+QcTbrQHaPcyuU9a7373dXefXtX2Duq3\/N8T\/v977W\/tfre71vrXWu9nwoIcDA2FuLi4sh6u0hOToY9e\/aS1fKo49D5fn6wJCgInj17RsrbR0DAIvDzm09Wy0LCoa5jx4L7l+5kvd1MdHcH13HjyWo5VDt0w\/owsLKyJqt5YGtjA8HBK8lqGaBDHz9+DJ10dSEj4xqKzYWM9HTQ0daBktJSUpqOc2fPgmV\/S8jMvE6KYkCHbt60CZycx6DQ3HB2cgL\/BQvJahouXvwVdHV1QEVFBS5dukyqYkCHDnZwgOPH41FoKLdv34bs7GyylMuNGzfg3r2\/yAJ4\/vw5farLiRNJYGpiSpZyuX\/\/PixYsAAdqf53dfx75crv9K1iUMnNzQFrNnY2pFs6evQImJqaYsBhYmIC6urqMGToUHSuMjh08CD069sXDA0NwcDAAFavDgFrayuIjNxJJepSUV4Offv0hZs3b5KiPE6fToP27dvD2tB1sD4sTDkOPXzoIIwY4UimfL6ePQsb5eTkDMXFJfCvH39Ee4LbF1RCcZz55Resy+2LL6GkpARiDhxAmx\/JySlUShgHe3uIPXiILOVRUVHBepJ7+Hlr+BZsq8Id+s\/ly8HL25tM+ZiZfAj6+gYYRImxt7Nj40MnshSHtZUldO6sDy9ekMAY7GAPampqUFZWRoowbhMmQFDQUrKahk0bNyjHod7MmYGBS8iUzd27d0BV9V3wnTWbFBEjHUeAlpY2WYqBd5f8YvjN\/4YUEQ72dtCbdaf1sTggAMaPn0BW06BUh0bulD0GiTl75gw26PBhySXBbsZGYGFhSZZiiD9+HOs+duw4KQAvWCCko60NEyd9RYps1oSshnFNvMigVIdu37GDTNmIx4D9B2JIYYN+Whpq69dvIEUxpKWmYj0REZGkAByJO4xa+NZtpMhm1crglvWENsShntOmYoN69+7DusAcuPrHH9DFQB8++NBEYkxVBA9YcKGjow3du78Pubm5GD3qdeoEbdq0gXPnz1Mp2bwJDl0Xuhavn8LnoQ116Pvdu4Mlm954enritKETu6CuruPgdkEBlVAsvMvv2vU9nK7Y2ztA927dQFNTCx4+fEglZPMmOPSHfftwqnf9+n9JUQwNcmgBcxq\/u3x9RQFRfl4e5Ofn42dl8ujRIwyQnj97DhbmZniDNYQ3waHKokEOTUpKRIfujt5DStNSUlyM7fH2mUmKfFodKsWe6N1gZWUF2U2w2iIELnRbWkJCYhIp8ml1aDOj1aFEVVUVRpV5NGbyz\/IO8TKXNJWVlYLlxcfdu3eppCR80f3WrVuCvxFqD18SFKIxDuVtkT7vm3rwNfQXtZfOGHIdevLkSRg5ciQ4Ojo26Fi7di39UpI\/s7IEy4uP8PCtVFKSzMxMcHZ2FvyN0DFv3jz6pSSNcai\/v7\/gud\/Ew83NDcrLy6nlIuQ6VN62lBDSd8ur0tj6ZdEYh76uOpVFo57Q5kJLGEMLCwshja\/ctTq0ebB921acyrU6tB7u3LkDpaXyt+eUAQ9Qc3JyyKrLgwcPYMTw4a0OlUdGRjpoa2vDT6mppDQdfL28v4U5LF4cSIokfG7Os0laHSoHC3NzGOE4kqymJzEhAbtVofVgPiO4evVq4x167do1iImJYX8z0ebzIZ5qoQwqnzzBOTHP6k9KSoKjR49KJIvJ4mUcmpJ8Ai9eekYGKTXwufET1pb09HSIjY3Fv68LvgnBz8lTfDg8EY\/P48X06dVLboYmOnRHRASZsnn29ClMmTwZ2rVrh8tuGhqazJ6CdmpqGpVSLOFbNmPSlbW1Ndja2oKmpgZ07WoIly7L35J6GYfa\/eNj6NGzF1k1FBYUQIcO6tCv3wdgY2MD5mZm6PgVK76jEnXZsnlTva9mFBUVYe6TlpYWWFhYgKGhEabOcLukpCaBb\/WqlVhfXp7w5kiDn9CARQvxREcpa+AYezq4rda2LQsalJPI\/NWkiVjnsmXL0c7JuQlt1dRg6KefoS0LnrHAt\/oaCg+E3nmnDfjM9CWlhpTkZGyDqZk5pmlyxjg7oZabm4e2NMuWBoGLy1iyhBnyyWBQU2tb3fPxXC9+TnPz\/miLuXD+HOoRMjIdVXx9fWG+VK6ONHxJjW8mj5\/gRooI\/c56YG4hWaGi4BNow67vgYmpGSkieKJYJ73OZAnjw25a94mTyKofcSbGtm3bSalhadAS\/O7S5SukAOsiY1D7939+IkWS0O\/XwJQpHmTVhW\/Y89+HhdVkfhSxeSXXvL0ld5SKi4tB9V1VmD7dixRJVFYGB8NMgTuxNgepwbWTsZ+zcUxToyNMnepJimK5lZ+Pbfj22xWkiOCJYnp6+mQJ4zR6NASvXEVW\/YiDD6HdnKFDPgEjI2OyROz\/YR+Wr+3QdetCYc6cOXgMGjQI+vTpU23zo4A5TMw38\/1Yj\/AOZoKIybrxPzznjlppN5wqNp7+jQ07LmNdSZFEJSkxET7\/fBSZwogf\/+zsmu2zayxY4Nr2HfWPv6+DZApSTtTKweWBiZamJnz62TBShLHs3x\/i4xPIqh9+TXhdcXFHSBHxlMUROtpaMEaq+\/Tx8sLyPGATw88RFRWFx1gXFxg4cFC1zY\/aGxnDhw0DDU0tskTsjY7Gc\/722yVSRDx6+BDas7jF1VU46U2FD8Y2g2wkBl5ponbtxJMnp5wkBWCqxxTULkpVqChCVq\/C+mrfsbt37UJN+sLXpqysFIyNjSXu\/vrgLznx834n9ebaTRZxct3G9mNS+OsOf0E7FkcMGzaClLp8vyYEJrMAUhbeM2bgkFZUVEyKaMrUoUNHXDCoDd\/o4GUDlwSRIgm+2zJunCtEy3nrubCwAKOtHj164g7MwgX++I\/p6uqxKYtkhYqCBx78H+FJ3Tydc2dkJLbBdZz8YGff3j0YNTaGqqpK0NXRgeFSbxQcPnQI6+THEnZBU1JSwIpF\/NraOhK9lzSBiwNg1KjRZNXl559P4zl5fadOnQKXMWPQtrNzoBI1JCbE43cpzA9CoEN5Qwexp1QeF3+9AB99ZI1jwYwZXvj6ob3DYPpWsfApk66ONnsKhsOmjRvZlKEftiMkJKTe3RE+FeDvljSWuXO+BlVVVfaE1CSh+c2bC23YWBdzIAbs7eyxDRPY1CIr608qIUxc3GHYsGEjWcLwOIWfz5QFfd7ePug0f4G35iZNdMfVKz7cCIEO5RgbGUF8QiJZ8uF3MJ9\/zp3rR4piybpxA\/\/BwEDhbkYW\/N0bHsC8TJppwe3bWGdERM30wJYFN\/x1DEXz+5UrWPf+\/QdIEVFefh\/10NAwUupS7VCenc4b25Au9Pgx0Rx07959pCiW6N1RWF9jAhueIdiTDREHYmJJaTw8+uzYUYNdyAp2UzzCNjiOlB9Avg4WL1qEdV3LFM1JOXza5jVjOhh06SLz6eRUO5SzbOlSGDBgIBvoJXfBpUmIj2fTlamQn3+LFMXCFzF4ffW9lCSmoqIcBg4Y8MovKPHufPbsWXD+\/AVM9vbw8IDEpIYlpr0KYWHrwMdnJlRWVpEi2k3xnDYNzp49R4owEg7lRLHIkZ+MR79vI2WlpSwC94DNW8JJaUkA\/B9YwvETp+xJjgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"117\" \/> evaluate (3 &oplus; 2) &oplus; (5 &oplus; 4). <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>10\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='20' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAgCAYAAAASYli2AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAOdSURBVEhL7VVbSFRRFB1LZwJNs590QgwExQx7QPnoIUmOg9Pjqyzrp6zGyKI0CR9YjZKlpiWUZoVZYmr2VR\/pVFA\/aWppWvnh0GikMuEzBV+4Omff49VrTR\/1WQs2M3utvde9c\/edfVSwg85OK4xGI16+fEX56Ogo5fbC0mGhOruG+shIqFQqlJc\/EAyg0+kQFBQkR1hYGBZpNFTX1fWFan5pGH\/8OBXxKC6+Jdif8eTxY6rJyMgUzC8MKx6UU1F6ejp9FhXdFIoSA\/39WOLmhuCQUMFIUBhaLB1kYjJlwPr5828NYw8dJL21tU0wEmTDyclJrAoIQHBwCOWt799Tw+3bdyifC0uHdOHde6IFMwvZ8FicEU5OTmhr+4DBwUGYzbXUlJeXj+HhYVElITUlmbSmt+8EMwvZkBfwcHR0lL\/PxPr1G0QVMDExAa2nJ1YGrBKMErJhSUkJCgsLUVBQQJGYmEBm0dHRqKqqElWzjyI5JVUwSiiGMhft7R+psbT0vmAk3Cu9S\/zTmhrBKGHXsKmpEe7u7uzO7wpGQm5ODvEtLS2CUcKuIZ96P3vXxsbGBCNheGiI+KmpKcEoYdfwT\/EvGpaVlSEqKgp6vf6vg\/uobDYbrFYrW6idfx3c5\/+UgarKSmzcGAofHx\/s3LkLdXV1QpHAc4PBQPrW8HA8f\/5CKBIUhjnZ2fTHj2QTM5lMcHN1hZodQs3NzaQ3NLyBRqOGr58fMjMzsdLfn+rr6utJ55ANe3t6sHDBAkQZtgsGbNm2UkNC4hnKd2w3wMHBATbbN8pHRkbg6roYmzdvwfT0NHGy4aPqh9Tc0NBIeV9fH312sHXfPzCAUdasZht9W4SO+BnE7NtLfUND0laXDc8mJdG2TktNwwpvb\/bTNPDy8kJ19SPSu7u7qdFoPEb5DE7GxxPfwhYvh2x49Mhh+jlqtRq5uVdQwxaoLiKCip+xB9\/+SVq4xjil4c2iQuJfi+EpDLlw6VK2YIApthP52avT6dEzc4fzDNPT0oivF4ORDS+cP0fC\/JNs3do18PX1w\/j4OOkx+w8IRcKR2Fjiv7ILcsiGz8xmEi5n5whGgqeHBzaJKfLXxFO7XCgSVgcGYtkyD9rwHLIhPx55g1qtQW2tmYZw4oT0wCsqKqnmxvXrlCcnp6C3t5e9t5cpz796jXQO2ZDjOzvQ+SBcXFzgwe6MH0ZX5xRzZGVdxNKl7tBqtXB2dsap0wlC4QB+AHKLH6mJ3saDAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>14\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='20' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAgCAYAAAASYli2AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAQuSURBVEhL7VZdTJtVGC4EGAMh4ccBHSMRwjCzm5nhd4GBNCoBOsfGoARM1EQpU+eFS8bATVScXmwsc9mmMMZY56ZMtosRUdGLQVZYgm0NZC2TQTGU0hZCmfyFv8fzvT39aMV44S71SU7yvc\/znuf7zk\/ftxK44fq1aygvL183hodNPAM4f\/6ch6bV6rjihIdhdlYWgoKCkJKS4jGsVhvpn316Al5eXlAqS\/D5mTPYvl2GqCgpRkZ+J12AaOhwTMHP1wfKklLOeGJsbAwSiQQvvpTDGWDo4UPiiotLOONm+KteR+KputPo7e3F3bsaTE9PcxVYWFhAX18fbDY7ZwALf0lRkZIzbobqK80khoSEYKO\/Pz0HBgai6XIzz1jD0NAQWltbkZWZifj4rRhkX+qCaHjs\/Woyee\/wYYyOjsJoNEIuzyau46efeZYTx48fQ0xMDGnpGbthsYxzxc1wdnaGluQO1x4V7NvPGSfm5+exsrKCez09CAjYiISEp\/Ho0R+kiYZ\/B8fUFBnu3PkcxYLR0tISPbtQVXmEcnQ6PcWioSI\/D0\/FxtKbXehnXywkH6k8ijHzKDZtepIt9wOuOlH+5huUM\/DgN4rX7eGhQ+\/CbDbDYDBAJpPB19ePXexhzM3NYbM0it1Db\/zY0YGJiQlcamykOXL5C+KHiIbLy8uoqFDB29sbPj4+lBgdHY22tu94BjAwYERyUhJprpuQn68QL76AdXtoZkvr6upCT889LC4uctYTer0enZ2deMCX6Y5\/PJR\/g\/+ioVqtRm5uLnJych57CD4Sm80Gk8nEatrIYw\/B5\/9TBhrq65GYmIi4uDgUFh5Y14R0Wi0KCvaSnpKaygrtTa444WF4UKWi32dxsRI1NTXw37CB1btA9PX3k67TafEEq+JbtsSgtrYWu9LSKL+l5QbpAkTDX1gfEURVxUHOAN0aDXGVR6so3r+vgGITO1EXtsbHQyrdTD1HgGj48UcfUrKVXaMVVnkmJyeJHxwcxJTDwcrXLAJYhUlN20W8C66yd\/++gWLRMD8vl\/XkYFRXVSMyMhJ+fn6IZft0+3Yb6eMWC00sLS2j2IVTJ08Sf\/PWLYpFw90ZGVQHg4KD8SU7mPb2dmSkp1PynTudGDAY6bms7BU+w4kfvm8nvvmKmmLRMJMZCsL1r7\/hDGtcMzPsUAKQl6eAzWolvfQvho0XG4i\/evUrikXDoqJCEizjay1RQALb9G3PyKiiezFdsedlrjhx4pNamqfp7qZYNDx39iwJLTe+5QywurqKsNBQPJ8tp+dnd+xAaGgYV53Yu0dBfcZun6BYNJyw29nkEESxK6DRdMPMmv3rr71KL3Fd3osN9RS\/9fY7GGcrudzURLFKtXbVREMBQmNPTk6if2AREREIDw\/HhQtfcNWJ03V1CAsLY3dPSn9VPE8d+BOhxvPRZA8iTAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu20":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>20 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>21<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">The ratio of milk and water in a mixture is 3 : 5. First, the volume of the mixture is increased by 25% by adding milk. Next, 40 litres of the mixture is replaced with water, after which 40 litres of the mixture is again replaced with water. If the final ratio of milk and water in the mixture is 1 : 7, find the initial volume of the mixture (in litres) present. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"64","CORRECT_ANSWER":"64","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu21":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>20 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>21<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">If M is the fifth power of a positive integer <i>x<\/i>, and the total number of factors of M is <i>f<\/i>, find <i>f <\/i>given that it is greater than 171 but less than 181. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"176","CORRECT_ANSWER":"176","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu22":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>22 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>28<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">Find the ratio of the perimeter of a regular hexagon and the polygon obtained by joining the midpoints of the hexagon. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><img height=\"18\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABMAAAASCAYAAAC5DOVpAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIrSURBVDhPlZK\/a1pRFMcfjZpKW9oOgiU\/+g+0lXSoxYqCgiBEXNW6iIOj6FRjNlMiNGRNtR0iWl0U2g4OIolZQjOkOMSmimIGTZFGVFDQQb\/JO14roeTZfuDC\/X7Pe9933z2HwwyazSY8Hg9cLtfMNTMsHo\/Dbrfj8PBw5poZ5nA4kEgkmBJGMGw4HEKn06FYLDJHGMGwcrkMvV5Pof+CYFgymYTVamUK+HV+juDmJpxOJ95tbeH3xQWrjBEM47u4vb1N+1KphMWFBXAcB5VKhbm5W1hafozT059U5xEMM5lM1CUe9SsVBZ2cFEj\/KBRI217bSfPcGNbpdKDRaNBut0nHolFEIhHaT7h39w6ePH3GlEBYNpuF2WxmaspoNEKv10M4HIJIJEb4w0dWEQgLBALw+\/1MTfn65TMeyeX0iy+ULzG8Cp9AYblcjk5Rr9fJ5LHZbEilUkxNOatWsb+\/j\/c7O5BKpVhdNWEwGFCNC4VCUCgU9CW3201mv9+HVqtFrVYjfRNrvjf03rejI9IcP5jdbpcuWyKRoNVqoVKpwGAw0AM8o6uhXfP5sLHxljljPsWiFJY7OCD958729vaoEAwGkU6naTAn8GHLS4tUr1bPyOOb8HxlBfPzt9FoNMi71gClUgmZTAaj0YhYLMbcMd+Pj\/HwwX2IxGI6tZw1YXd3Oi7XwjKZDD0wPkGVuVP4y19f98NiscDr9SKfz7PKmL9GQ61WU0P+H+ASb3h\/Nu6O6G0AAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"19\" \/>&nbsp;: 1 <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT2":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\">2 : <img height=\"18\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABMAAAASCAYAAAC5DOVpAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIrSURBVDhPlZK\/a1pRFMcfjZpKW9oOgiU\/+g+0lXSoxYqCgiBEXNW6iIOj6FRjNlMiNGRNtR0iWl0U2g4OIolZQjOkOMSmimIGTZFGVFDQQb\/JO14roeTZfuDC\/X7Pe9933z2HwwyazSY8Hg9cLtfMNTMsHo\/Dbrfj8PBw5poZ5nA4kEgkmBJGMGw4HEKn06FYLDJHGMGwcrkMvV5Pof+CYFgymYTVamUK+HV+juDmJpxOJ95tbeH3xQWrjBEM47u4vb1N+1KphMWFBXAcB5VKhbm5W1hafozT059U5xEMM5lM1CUe9SsVBZ2cFEj\/KBRI217bSfPcGNbpdKDRaNBut0nHolFEIhHaT7h39w6ePH3GlEBYNpuF2WxmaspoNEKv10M4HIJIJEb4w0dWEQgLBALw+\/1MTfn65TMeyeX0iy+ULzG8Cp9AYblcjk5Rr9fJ5LHZbEilUkxNOatWsb+\/j\/c7O5BKpVhdNWEwGFCNC4VCUCgU9CW3201mv9+HVqtFrVYjfRNrvjf03rejI9IcP5jdbpcuWyKRoNVqoVKpwGAw0AM8o6uhXfP5sLHxljljPsWiFJY7OCD958729vaoEAwGkU6naTAn8GHLS4tUr1bPyOOb8HxlBfPzt9FoNMi71gClUgmZTAaj0YhYLMbcMd+Pj\/HwwX2IxGI6tZw1YXd3Oi7XwjKZDD0wPkGVuVP4y19f98NiscDr9SKfz7PKmL9GQ61WU0P+H+ASb3h\/Nu6O6G0AAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"19\" \/> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT3":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><img height=\"18\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABMAAAASCAYAAAC5DOVpAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIHSURBVDhPlZPPi5JBGMdf8B9o8aS0Bw+aBwOhAqFFQcGbvF0111IXRKyDu102jx4Vq6NsUCLoRWGDzQrePLSobaftqIgnr\/4K2cQf+815nNRl1\/etDwzM95l5P++8M+8IUKDT6SAajSIUCik2RVkul4PX60W1WlVsijK\/3498Ps+TPLKy2WwGu92Oer3OK\/LIyprNJhwOB0n\/BVlZoVCA2+3mCfh9cYF0Oo29vSDC4TBOTj7ykQWyMnaKqVSK+r8GAzy4fw+CIMBisUCv11N\/\/+AFjTNkZS6XC5VKhfrPn0Xo4UKxSJnx2OOmWq32nfJG2WC+EqvVil6vRzmZTMK7u0v9v3z5\/Ilkr16\/obxRJkkSRFHk6WYO9qMkOzv7QXmjLB6PIxaL8XSdn+fnJBLFR7zCZeVyGcFgEMPhkIoMj8eD4tr+rHN6+g1bW7dgMNxBl28DQ2BHbTQa6S2JRIKKo9EINpsN7Xab8jofjo9p7sOdHXS7KxFDYD9mv9+fv8UAtVqNyWSCRqMBp9PJp6x4e3REoidP\/RiPx7y6Yrln7EKzidlsFqVSiT57nRq7yFy0iaVsOp1Cp9PRCtl+ZTIZPgJcXs5w12QimUajwfb2bWi12mV7934x98ppMgF7QKVSodVq8eriwr88PEQkEkEgEIDP57vSJOkrzbv2a5jmKzCbzTz9D8AfbTp8g\/8ttkYAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"19\" \/>&nbsp;: 1 <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT4":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\">3 : 2 <img height=\"18\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABMAAAASCAYAAAC5DOVpAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIHSURBVDhPlZPPi5JBGMdf8B9o8aS0Bw+aBwOhAqFFQcGbvF0111IXRKyDu102jx4Vq6NsUCLoRWGDzQrePLSobaftqIgnr\/4K2cQf+815nNRl1\/etDwzM95l5P++8M+8IUKDT6SAajSIUCik2RVkul4PX60W1WlVsijK\/3498Ps+TPLKy2WwGu92Oer3OK\/LIyprNJhwOB0n\/BVlZoVCA2+3mCfh9cYF0Oo29vSDC4TBOTj7ykQWyMnaKqVSK+r8GAzy4fw+CIMBisUCv11N\/\/+AFjTNkZS6XC5VKhfrPn0Xo4UKxSJnx2OOmWq32nfJG2WC+EqvVil6vRzmZTMK7u0v9v3z5\/Ilkr16\/obxRJkkSRFHk6WYO9qMkOzv7QXmjLB6PIxaL8XSdn+fnJBLFR7zCZeVyGcFgEMPhkIoMj8eD4tr+rHN6+g1bW7dgMNxBl28DQ2BHbTQa6S2JRIKKo9EINpsN7Xab8jofjo9p7sOdHXS7KxFDYD9mv9+fv8UAtVqNyWSCRqMBp9PJp6x4e3REoidP\/RiPx7y6Yrln7EKzidlsFqVSiT57nRq7yFy0iaVsOp1Cp9PRCtl+ZTIZPgJcXs5w12QimUajwfb2bWi12mV7934x98ppMgF7QKVSodVq8eriwr88PEQkEkEgEIDP57vSJOkrzbv2a5jmKzCbzTz9D8AfbTp8g\/8ttkYAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"19\" \/> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu23":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>22 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>28<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">If the product and the sum of all possible values of <i>x <\/i>satisfying the equation 3<em>x<\/em><sup>3<\/sup> &minus; 31<em>x<\/em><sup>2<\/sup> + 76<em>x<\/em> &minus; 22 = 0 are denoted by P and S respectively, find the value of S &minus; P. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>3\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAfCAYAAAAx6zerAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAINSURBVDhPzZRNbxJhFIUH64pIidCZBbRT2rhTY\/f4gdv6Cxp\/AGFbw466A0QI1W4rNVI2JdWNn6lhVTcMTQnd0RQhFRfDl6Ehtlbg+M5lOgU7sO5J7uK850nmvnfuDIchWo\/H4Xa7IcuyegLowt8LBYybTDAYDKhUq+qpDnx01ITdZoPVYmXwFeT399VEB340P4+bt25jORoFx3HI54fAL5Z7wOHhD9bzm+Hwzk4GV8fGsLGRJB9bXSVYlivkFRHc6XQwZbeD5wUkEgnEYjE8XlggOBAIIpfbO4f\/np6Cn5iA2Wwm4P8KBJ+dw4oajQbq9bpWoWCQQEnK4PfxMTEDF+xXNBIh+OCgoJ6MgL9tb8Pr9aJSGfFSRumywJIkIRwOIxQKjSyF4VKplG6oV5dxGn9OTvCKrabH44Hf70e5XFaTnjS42Wzi\/r27tA9OpxMWy3VYrFak02mV6IOfLvkI\/PT5C\/lfbAvHTdfwwPWQvCINzrB5x9nn368bs7OwT06h2+2Sv3DBdruNYrGIlZWXMBqNWFt7rSY68F4uBxv7FSgtieI0u+RPNdGBW60WTSGbzWJmxoFphwPVao2yAfistzO9e7tJT3j\/4SN5DX6yuIg7c3Oq62kzmSR4a+sreQ0OP2eLwgKfbwm1Wg3Z3V0IPI9JNg3lHSgaaCPC1pBngCiKEAQBLpcLpVJJTYF\/Fg9ympV+T94AAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>5\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='18' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABIAAAAgCAYAAAAffCjxAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAALUSURBVEhL5ZZdSFNhGMcXYjgvJpjIwGwXdi86p17aB+UKTN3syowKmiV2UUngog+VXbTMPjRMmKBeOHdjUy\/mzCxwaEjlB27ZxUbahd0IbpNtWvv3nmevuHkmmt3VH17OeX7Pc\/68H+d9z5Fgm0LBIGpqajA7N8fJlkbsduh0OmpdXd2cRiQyun6tGhKJBJOTHziJ6Pmzp0hMTERJSQk05eVUU1d3h2ejjCYnJpCnzKUCodntIzwDzM7MELuqq+YEuHL5ErGPnz5TTEY\/NzYI5qnyYTAY6H542E4Fgh7cv0cswIa9qWAgAKvVipWVFYrJaD0Ugs1mI\/D+3ZjISH36FNLT5ejo6EB2djYUCgVqa28gHOYFTKI5GhywiowKVCpIpVLIZDLo9Xro6+upJlepxNraGtWIjIYGB8RG+fnE+vtfcwKYe3uJmc19FO\/J6OSJ42zFDiLIpmBT35eWqO5hQyPFezK6q48Mxel0cQK4nE5iL1rbKN5xjmy2YU6ALy4XMbX6LK2Sd3UV6uJiYt8WF6lmTz0S1Gky4QDjSUlJSE6WIiEhASZTJ8\/GMfL5vJifn2dXPydb8njc6OnpYdujC263m9OIREb71b9sZLFYoNVqUVZWtu+m0Wgg8Xg8mJqa+uv2v65aS8sTFBYWQMXOI6PxMULr6zwjVlyjcPgXLlRW0p7TaitQzb4awn2x+gzLRR2LUYprNDM9TQ\/evHWbE6CpsYHY+LiDk1jFNfL5fHA4HPB6fZwAL9tayWj07Rgnsdp1sp3sAOtmu12hOIKKivN\/NrRolZaeQ1raIerNI6ORU7F2NfL7\/Qiwb5ihqYnMmptbeCZWOxoJD2+X0DOlMo9HsYprNDr6BnK5HAODQ5wIr0QYKSkyFBUd4yRWcY2+LizQmZyVdZSO3R\/Ly7hYVUVDM\/dZeFWsdhya8OOQm5OD1NRUZGRk4HBmJtrbX\/HsdgG\/AZSWrFxChx6jAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu24":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>22 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>28<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">Find the value of <i>x<\/i>, if <img src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABsAAAAkCAYAAAB4+EEtAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAQuSURBVFhH7ZdtTFtVGMdb3sJgGTgSofsyhlnNYO2mRjoJiJnJJFFDQoiGiR9gEAJhnQGBGZk6Z2CZTCDrpEP8yMwgbDJeEsLgA1NGCZBQXoqTEQKbGYQCHQiUAn\/vee4ZiOWWAvLBxF9y0j7\/55z+c+6555ynMmyAVqtFc3Mzj9aoqKhASkoKtUuXvsHY2BjPiFRVVUGn06G4uHi13RLGPMfO7ELu55DJZCgvv8kVEe3ZdLi5ueHUqXeQkJAArz17oNGcwOzsn7wHoAjwh5eXF\/z8\/Fbbu++9z7N\/M+vs6EBERDgZsVZa+gPPAPV1taRlZedwBWi610jaR\/EfU2wwtFF87ZoO8\/PzmJubw\/T0NGZmZijPILOVlRXIhY5HjgSjsLCQBun1N6gDo6urE+np6Rh9\/JgrIu5urnjl1dfo+49lZZC7uKC724ipqSky+ydktrS0hPr6ehJ+GzDZmW1Ec1MT9fviy68o\/uScFq6urlAqlfD09ISHhwfi4k4Lj3mW8gy7NTO0PdjU7PeHD+G3fz8OK1+GxfKMNE3o6zQuOycHra2tuFpQQPGbkW\/RZBh2Zu382UuZGbu78YKvLwIPBWF0dJSrbJwB1dXVPBLJzvqUfqvl\/i8Ub8ms+uc7lDt58m1MTk5yVZqfbpZTf53ue4qdNruhLyE9N\/cCV9YwT0wgMjISGRmZXBHJz8ujMfelZvZ8zUpK9FwRtkVnJ2khIUfR0tKCJuHlaGhooGYQHp\/VuoCgQ4HU51dhvRhdwpi93t5QqdRYXLSRtsHM7M2Sk86QtlFTqY5Rn77eXnoTmaZQKOgzODgE\/f0myjPszNj+6BUGms1ra\/JocJC0np4eGI3GdW1w8BHvBVgXFmgLlQl7rq6uDtbFRZ4RsTPbTf43+1eQVVZWIjY2FjExMbvamIdsaGiI9kp7e\/uuNubx31gzdmeZTCb6dJZtmV3Oz6ejyN3dncqAvPzLPOOYLZvduX2bjqKz2nM0s8\/On6e4pqaW95Bmy2YmUz++vXKFRxAOWSuZFVz9jivSbHvN2H1WVFSEsLAwHDt+HBNmM89Is20zVo2p1erVkm5kZIRnpHHKjN1fAwMDPFrPH0+eIMD\/RWhOvEFVmiM2NdOXiDd0b28fxRaLxc44LTWV+lieicWPFJuaRYSHwz8ggEfA1xcviuZ9orlNuLOUysNUaS0vL5MmhaQZq2bT0lLhs28f7aWMzEzYbDYMDw\/jwAEFvL33Ij4+Hi8FBUEul6Ox8R4fKY2k2fj4OBITE2kW0dHR0F2\/vromrITLzspCVFQUkpKT0SHUG87g8DHW1twlswdtbVzZGQ7Nks6Ihc7Tp+v\/Gm0Xh2Zq1VEcPBiI5U1eaWeRNJsSTggX4V\/JBx\/GcWXnSJqx2p09Qr2+lCs7R9KMnQy+Pj4IDdUIZ2AxV3cC8BehJC1AWai89QAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align: middle; width: 24px; height: 32px;\" \/> = <img src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABMAAAAjCAYAAAB2KjFhAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAANHSURBVEhL3ZbdL5tRHMfLjdcwL92EKy81qSVMbMwSFcmGsZttLEuGZZHoC7Y79gdQ1+YldmmraiO2GyStbW6MTe+QmZcpZTTxspaFxvju6a9H6+EROjfLPslJer7n93ySc87znFMRGC\/q6lBZWSnYpqamqKa\/v09wfGNjg8bdMoVcjpycHHfLy8tDUFAgRCIR5ucXqKa8rBSBgYG8uvz8Auzv07BHdpQP7wdIVN+gpv7u7i6iLl1EwZ1C6gshKLPbbIgID0dmZhZLgJXlZZLX1taht7cX3d3dsFgsbNSFoKxKqaAHx8cnWAIYjQbKAgICIBaL4e\/vDx9fX7S3v2IVArIfS0v0UHFxCUtc6HU6hIWFoYGb9vb2NtbX1vDg\/j2qHRn5TDXHZOqGeioYHTWxxIPD4WC\/XEx9m6RapaqK+jzZPrctlxMlSEhIZIkHq9WKiQnPtJ1YLAske1xaRn2ebN5spsGaZ89Z4uHpk3Iam\/0+xxJA19VFmVbbRX2erI\/bpcODh\/k0NERjUmkyNBoNmptfUj89\/Zp7+jzZgNGIoqIimEzH18uJwWCALDsbERERiIqKglyuwPr6OhsV2ICz4HyBnet7lL+SncQ\/LJuenqbvTK\/Xn6s5HaKenh4olUooFIpzNafjP9gAI\/fCyuWVqKiooDUS4kyyRrWaPp3U1FTuwMyk3yp2UhzmVNmvrS16uLDwLku4w1OlomxxcYklLk6V\/eY+nY6ODszMzLIE0Lx5TbI58zxLXHi9AY6dHYgjI3Hrdh729vZY6kJQ5rwoDp8GB6yuruJm1g2kcGtns9lZ6uGYTNelRXR0DBYW+DfP+NgYYmJicD0jA5ubWyzlc0x2JVmKBAn\/2DaNfkFoSAiqq2tYIoxbZrfb0draiiDuxo6Ni4ems5Pyn9zVfyE0lLvaAtDW1oaWlhY0NTVxJ20zN1Ub1RzglpnNc5DJsmmXZDIZ1OpGykeGh5GWlkbvV1JSEiQSCTWpVMq9GotUcwBvmnqd64L4OjnJEteNdVZ4skcPS+Dn53\/iAp8GTxYfF4uUlKus5z1umdW6Ah8fH+5cUrHEe9yywcGPtF49b9+xxHvcsmnu32FwcDByc3PR2allqTcAfwBABuN6tAi90wAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align: middle; width: 16px; height: 36px;\" \/> = 2<sup>2<\/sup><sup>x<\/sup>. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='47' Height= '15' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAC8AAAAPCAYAAAB0i5aaAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAARzSURBVEhLxZZpTFxVFMeHZSCAkLIq67AGZEhl80MxBazWJljFwsQUpgvYwgAtWAT0S7FWgSqRLyQsYmqKIcVSNIipXywKJGWRJhQdklpaoC0tVJYZtgHD8vfeM3fYo20k9ZfczDvnf959Z+49574nqampwXs5udDp5vB\/cb2rC5mZJ6FSqdhvFrq6rgsFaGhoQGlp6bpRXl6OyspKSJRKJRydnhWhT5\/WlhbY2drC3z8Aqamp8PH2hp29PTo6fyU94eBB2DLdMJycnGBtbQ2JRAIJ\/7f2Do7Qaicp+GkyNTUFYyMjPOfsgtlZHfn+fPQI7m6ucGa++fl5TE9PY2JigoZGo0F\/\/x24ODsj+uU9q8lrNFq6eW5uDh+dOYOgoCD4+Pggha3G7dt3SOMsLS2hgm2bXC4n\/ZOCAhQVFuL06XwR8fjw5LOyslD\/7XfCo+fAW7G0sveHhoRnlaSjR0gbevBgNfmZmVksLi4gOiqSxLS0dHx89ixMTU1hZ2ePwcG7dHP2qVOkJyYq8WF+Pmx37CDbw0NG+n9Fp9PBydERgfIgWqi1dHZ00LNyc98neyV5Tv3lOhKLiz8nm9Pd3U2+4ymptFL8Oi5OIVSg79Yt+oNy9rCt+K2nB319fcL6d1QpKfSMq1ebhGeVPdHReIbV+\/TMDNnrkj+WnAxjYxNotPoSMhAWEgz\/gOfx45UrNHHD941C0RPKdE9PL2Gt0qtWw4jV9NGkZOH5Z1SsRPn8RefOCc8qavXvpPGT0cC65A8pEyE1M8PCwgLZBt58Yz\/c3NxRV3eJJvhpw6pERe7eVDa82fz9\/Cg+I+OE8G4Nb8T9r8dQ7MXaWuFdT3a2vlzV6l7h2ZB8RnoardTw8AjZBmQe7ggODkVLczNNUPlFlVD0eMo8WPP6CkvPkcOH2G4FwJc1dVLyO8K7GS3b5bDQUFhaWqG9o1N417O8vMyOUC94yDyFR89K8kssoKX5F0pOpUoXMuuD+svky8v7gCbhx5Sbu\/vKH6woLyN9584XyObUXfqGfDdv\/sESC0Gi8rBQNqOIO0CxvMb5jvNdMByLhoYdGRmGEYtRbpiHkjdida7VTpEjNeU4TRYe\/iJiYvRbGRYWjtGxMdJ\/bmqClaUlpFIpO4udSTdjpRYYKCd9+OFDmDHt\/PmvyPbz9WUrf4yuN9LR3kb382Fubr5yzYdUaoZ79+5TXHubPq6gsIhsA5LW1lZcuFDNavQv4QJqay8iISEBCoUCVVVfUv1y+MosLC5ibHQUFRUVKCkpQW9vLxzs7bA7MopiXtq1i\/rj2rU28LldXVyx97V9uHGjh\/S1DAz00zz8Vb\/xE6CsrJxeUPq4AYpZW+8cifh9LO4ODsLGxgafflYsPPqjkK9KTk4e2bw\/HBwcYGVlBQsLC+ohExMTvPLqXtK3kydKnr\/EFPHxlGxERARiY\/VvQi9vn5Ut5g3Ia3Z8fJyGp0yGeMXbmJzc\/s+PJ0rewA+NjTiRkUFfgdXVXwvv1oSGhOBk5rvC2k6AvwH+pdUS+7nxAQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='48' Height= '15' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADAAAAAPCAYAAACiLkz\/AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAASJSURBVEhLxVZtUFRVGF6+HFhQFthyqpH4DDIbhxppcsZsAsLAwGF1ZeQz+wFpEy6xmf4LNljArVxAGU3Qhl1BG3EHImmScSAgFT8SEJv8IxOp7PJNQ8DC0znvvcuHJsHk5DNz9t73ed5z97z3fc97rqSiogIqlQqjo3\/iSWHKakVZ2TGkpaXROHBAh6HhYVEVUFVVieLiYuj1+plRU1MLSUJCAjw8PEW3J4OkxEQ4ODggNjYWieze0dERYeERmJ6eJn1ycgIeMndIpVK2Vo+ZkZL6HiQ8YpnMAxZLHzn\/3yguKoJEIoE2v0BkAKPRQFzmx1lknz\/\/I9lHvz6GwcFBGv39\/RgZGZkNwGy2kLPVOgltXh5CQkLg7++P+Ph4tLVdIc0Gk+ks1q9\/nfSUlFSW\/jJKfU9Pj+ixeNSfO4f09HQMzymZ4eEhWvCGDRvJ\/lKng52dHf64e5fsuZgJoH9ggIiYdzfTZJ7K3NxcyOVekLDJPzU3k25ge4broaGvQaPR4OU1a8jm4\/r1X8jnv+Lb06fpefkFhWSnpiTDxcUFSqWSXhp\/uXqWOY6ZAKxTU\/ihvp4mqtV7SeS4x6JevtwNIa+8yrJjhb+fL3x8fFl9ig4MIWvX0rz29g6RmQVPd2trK6vjSZFZGBaLBV6enggICGSZGCEuOCiInh8VHY2CggJER0WRnZ2jmQ2AI3NPBgnd3d1k25CYsIOy0NLcQnqW+hNREfC5JueRAYSHvUWamS3s33Dt2lX4PO8NLy852js6RRZoaGiAwWAQLQHKrQp67rwAdu\/6gMjBoSGybdj36V7i676royuPfC70B78i\/sEAcrI\/I95dJoOlb+Em8X1dHZY5OSEoKBi\/L2IvHS8vp2fPC8C20K5bv5JtQ0R4GJycllGNc31HQqKoCPhw966HAmi8cAH29vbYwlqjVOq6YAAnjUaar9wej\/HxCZEVYO7txf59+1FZWSUyAor0B+cHMDExiatX2ohUbN0mugE\/s\/q1Yxzvyxybo4X6a2E8x6WLF2mPcO7GjXbiBlhDcHWVIjcvn23IU6Q9KoDOjg4WqB3e2PgmmzfIDtRRapG2Nmk299J8ufwptp+EyuD8i8FB8PPzFwLgDrY2qs7KInv16pcQExND96tWeaOr6xbp3XfuIDAwgHhvb2+68g7Br7YMRL4dgXXrQun+eHkZaeMT89+sDVHvbCL9n0Zk5CbyOXz4ENkrVrgjLi4OK1c+PVsRjY2NKGf1NDY2Rs4cZ6urkZycBIVCAZ3uC3obHPxk5H5\/sWFkaS8sLKRMJLHTnP8B7xpHjxyh+xMnvkFTUxP2ZHxEdk1tLYYe2Fsc\/L9KS0tRUlIy7zOBD5PJJHoBly9fQkZGBq1JpcpE582bxEvod5Hg3yx+vj7YptwuMgIXwHrzM88+R\/b7O3fSMS9jG5dnxoltTB6As7MzmluEsnucWFIAHJqcbFpQYOAL9DY82WK5feZMNem2Gu5jNc9HvjaP9N9u3170WbAULDkADp5OtVpNnw9arRb37t8XlYdRedIINzc30XrcAP4Gv8DmIzUhQo8AAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='38' Height= '15' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACYAAAAPCAYAAACInr1QAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAPNSURBVEhLxZVfTFN3FMc7CgoBeSEU0IHDMmor7RIqdSZgXJZtdg\/shW1VAmqdK3+CiUqyyVYMqLgBo0YCS5yLNilMqA+ABjFZXQQxqMuUlRcywx40gCSFauQ\/7Xe\/37m\/Ak2Mgg\/uk9z2d8733HvOvefc35U5HA6UlpZiamoa\/wfeiQmcrqqCxWJBSckh9Pf3k1+Wm5uLuLh4Mt40fr8PH+zciZiYGOTl5UGv17Na4uAeGICMVxobq4DX+1SEvzkOmPdDJpOhp+cW2bOzM0hKfBuGbduXCpuY8JI4PT2N4+XlSEvbAqVSiYKCAgwNDZHGWVhYQH39WWg0aqSkpOD0Dz\/iRGUlKioqRcTKud3bC4ejSVgS2wwZiItPWCrs+fNJzM\/PY0dWFt1FUVERS1YBuTyE9EePHtOJxczP9fz8vbBarYiOXkd2aqqK9NfB5\/NhdHQU9osXERERgYaGxqXCOK0tlyhJ7U91ZHP+vHdPKrS4hLXbS2vT7j1CBQbcboSEvAX91gzh4U99Cs3NzaipqYHT6aQuvAy3+28oFAq6dmCsggrbtzcfoaFh8D4NnjedNg1a3XvoaG+nkzs7rwlFQr1ZBbV6C61HRkag02kpLikpif7T0\/WLo\/IinrF8g4OD6Ovrw7spSmi1uuDC9uw2ITw8guZoOcZdnyB5k5I9hSZKdPNmt1AkDBkZUKnUtC4uLKSYXjY\/nMvOVrKrq2vJfhVd1zopPqiwAsvXrC1yjD55QnaADRvWszflfdxw\/U4nXbhgF4pEQnw80thdcvicWK3ltA6wLioKBw9ahCXh9\/vxy7lzOFZWJjwS\/Q8eBBfmY4F\/3HCRs7CoWIQBLZd+I1\/Zd9\/TkCoUsUhO3oSxsTHSbXV1pPPCX4SztYX0jitXhWeJT427SOu5JT1dzpdffE4+KkwuD2Vz9YyErw6YpUQGA4xG42JSj2ec9OtdXQhfuxZr2JGQwF5rpq8JC0O6fivpy7l\/\/y82s3IcPnJUeIL5l21D72zcSNfguTQaDa2ra2oh6+7uht1ux8zMrAgHmpuaYDKZkJOTg\/Pnf2Ubn6Tx7YTP3xhrdWNjA+psNgywXToqMhIffvQxxQRob2ujJPwz8zI8Hg+q2CeJ5zKbzXC5XOSX0e8KefjwH7ZvRcNmOyM8wN27d6iAb749JjzAGZvU3obGn4Vn9ayqsLm5OXyWnU1JMzMzkS3WqSoVhoeHKeZKRwf5Tp48RfHj4+P0VCYnp0hfKasqLEAbaxP\/MvD5dLC2L2dHViYiWWvVajUSExMXj7P19SJiJQD\/AdeDEmOBEXwcAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='54' Height= '15' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADUAAAAPCAYAAABEB4e7AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAUVSURBVEhLzZZrTFRHFMcXEJDVAtUFNlRBQGiJ5WGkYLUQk9IvKqUNWBEUbKRFwVqErQIqDx9Qs6IxKVaImhawUVsFlAQSAbVSQRI0VmEtsSo+eWldWFxU8N+Zc2d3gRpTEz7wS2Yz53\/O7D3n3nnJSktLoVKpoNfrMV55\/vw5CgsL0dTUJBSJyspTKCgowN69e42t4uRJyGJiYuDkpBRh45OdeXmQyWTI+36nUCS8PD1hI5fDwcHB2OJWfglZQkICMxyh1faK0PHFyYpyKoi3zKxsoQKa1laYmcmwfUcu+vr6qGm1WvT395uKevJES8G9zKFKTYWn50y4uLggNjYOGs118nEGBgaQl5sLd3d35ndFZmYW0jZuxObNm0XE2NHR0QErK0tERERigoUFMjaZnnHi+HEq9NLly0IxYSzq6VM9JRwwZw4Fp6enY8+ePZDLbWBnZ4+bt27TgJVxseRft+5bqNVqKBQKsmfN8iH\/WDJ\/3ofw8fFFV1cn+ypmSM\/YJDxATnYWaYsWLsS0adPg4eGB7Owc8hmL4hT\/\/BMluL+wiGxOy7VrpH2dsBrd3d3Uj4\/\/SniBtra\/YG5ujsDAuUKRaG1pQf7u3RgcHBQK8ODBA1RVVaGsrMzYmpubhXckW3Oy6Vl37t6Drq+X+sOLCv80jLSwsDAcOnQI8atWkZ28PmVkUbErlmOCpSV0un6yDcz294Ovrx\/KTkifvKamVngk3vXygs\/7vsIC7t+\/B7cZruxNWkDPvr6BtI0baPyUKVOMLTExSXhNnKmro7gjR46S3av9h+ycrdvI5mg0Gpw6VSksicQ1qyluRFHRy6IwcaINe7tDZBv4JPRjeMz0xC+HD9Og+vo\/hEditr+\/cfodO3oUdra2FOfq6oaBZ89I54QEByPgg0BhSbx48UL0TPCXxMeHhoYiJCQEQUFBZE9na3xZdAxevhSBo\/jt12P\/LeqbtUk0T++yTz4cB7ZugoNDUH\/+PA36cX+h8ABDQ4N4294ecwIC2cNesgQCsW37DiyJjIQtW4uGoobYNFQ6OdKWW1FeTm9Zp9ORbzQpKSkIDw\/HggULqKi5w4qKWb6C7XBPkZSYiC2ZmWKExP59BaaiFAoHltwQmi5eJDEicgnZnPz8XaSp1bvI5tNq6lQFWlpa8fjxY6xPTib\/vPkfUVGGRKOWfgH5pMnGom7dvElx\/KU5OztT39HREQ2NjeR\/Hb3aJxSfnbOVbL5OXV2mk3bpkrT7dTx8iBksN18\/f6kouXyS8ZzKytxCwc7O78Db25v6fEvV66W18eeVK+wPXUiXs4PPlk01a2trBAaN3CiWREZg0uS3jEVdv66hafQDuwHwpNrb2+HuNgNeXu+xKWjaTF7F3Tvt9LxU1XdCARobGqBUOpHuz6a\/3MYGCnb43rp9GzK+4M6d+33E3G64cIFtj1l09pw5e1aooIONJ8OvVHW1taiurkZPTw+sraywOCxcREmMLupVpG2QNo6H7Dx6HQMDerY51eDGjRtCkXj06BEOHjiAjIwMui51dnaRLqPf\/8nf7E95EklJa4UClBYXk6ZW5wtFYnRR\/N5WUlJCfQNrVifQWJ7cWPJGRfE1o1KlUiJKpZLdOjypv2jRYujYVxzO55+Fw9LK2lhUOTuTeGxaWjoVUXP6NDvfzBAVFU3+seSNijLQ1taGgwcPoKioCFevXhXqSFSpKfDzny0siX1sivDNgV+\/+Bm1NCpKeMYS4F+ztOT54SPHCgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu25":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>22 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>28<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">After a batsman scored 35, 46 and 39 runs in his fifth, sixth and seventh innings, he observed that his average runs scored per inning in his first seven innings was less than that in his first four innings. If his average runs scored per inning in his first eight innings was equal to 39, then the number of runs that he scored in his eighth inning was at most <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>28.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>31.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>71.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>68.\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu26":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>22 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>28<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">A certain sum under a certain rate of compound interest becomes three times itself in eight years. After how many years will the sum become 27 times itself? <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>16\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>21\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>24\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>32\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu27":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>22 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>28<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">How many pairs of natural numbers exist such that when the LCM of the numbers is added to their sum a total of 49 is obtained? <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>1\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>2\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>3\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>6\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu28":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>22 <\/i><i>to <\/i><i>28<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">The ratio of the number of boys and girls in a class is 5 : 3. If the average weight of all the boys is 63 kg, whereas that of the girls is 47 kg, find the average weight of all the students in the class. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>54 kg\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>57 kg\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>58 kg\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>59 kg\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu29":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>29<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\">If <i>x <\/i>and <i>y <\/i>are positive integers, for how many pairs (<i>x<\/i>, <i>y<\/i>) will&nbsp; <img src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAGUAAABdCAYAAAC8VagPAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAA9DSURBVHhe7Z0JWI1pG8eZUfY1ZQuVtVJCQgbNIEWylbl8+CrLN3NdjCXNjC3MYms0I2VsE2EwBjNGRjGGT7RaIio7LUqWGDWEzP2993Pu03be95z3bDrnfOd3Xc\/lfe735Knnf95nvZ\/7rQEGzMuXL2HF8uXw0UcfsTRjxky4ffs23dVdDFqUeYFzwcTEBObNC4KQkBBo0qQJ9O3nSnd1F4MVpbioCGrUqAEBU6aSBeCnPbuZ7cSJk2TRTQxWlH\/++QfOnz8Hjx4\/JgvA79HRTJSEhESy6CbVLsqlS5fg0aNHlBMPVnrqhQuUU0zJixfQ3MwMBgwYBK9fvyarblJtomClzv\/8c5g7dy4UFBSQVTz481HbtoG3tzfcuXOXrPzcy82FXr16gpNTD3j27BlZdZdqEeVNaSl4DBsGAQFTyKI6e3bvhvbt2kFGRiZZKpOSkgzm5ubQz9UVioqKyarbVIsoUwMCYORIb8qpDwrToUNHePrXX2SRkJAQD\/Xq1YNPZs0mi37w1kU5\/scxsLRsCy+4Nl6TfDh+PPj5+VMOoJDr4Bs2aACmpqawdu1aCA0NZcNiTNnZOfQp3eSti+LSuzeErQunnObIzs6C5s2bwy2aHJ45fRp69OgBLi4u0KlTJ+5J6lCWkpOT2Wd0lbcqysXUVGjf3gpKSl6SRbOMHTMGgoI+Zdc4ENBXeEUp4kYop7lvWlZWNlkASrnO+cyZM4Idqhi+WLoUPIePoJwwhYWPWVl5eflk4Ya0JS\/Y73Tz5k2yyPLz3r3QTw9m7IrgFaWwsBAaN2rEfautyQLgNXw4m3jFxh4li\/IMc3eH1SHfUE6YvHv3oNa774JTj55kAXivvyu8W6sW13knkEWWnJwc1jxVnDDqI4LNV3hYGBPh9Jl4CFm9il3v3vMT3VUebE7s7ezgVNxpsshnSfBiVmZa2mX4NGgeu46JjaW7\/Lx58wYcHRwgXo5w+oCgKDg6wj+wZctWrEK+\/PIruqMa+fl5YNbMDK5evUYW+Tx98gRsbKyhTZs2rPyIiPV0Rz59+rjApk2bKaefyO3o10eEswrxHjWaLKpz5fJlaNu2rcxcQh7YB2H5fv4BZFGMr+84WLbsC8rpJ4KiZGdnQ5vWrVml9HJ2Zk2DOqRfuQJdu3aFkpfiRl6ZmZnQpHFjVv4HHwwmq2J8fcbBV18vp5x+wisKNh1WVu2hXbv2EMZNvLBiIiO30l3VQFE6d+4Mz0VMGrGjx8VDBwdHrj9bzco\/+NshuisfgxTlHlchTk7dWUWkcU0O0qVzJzAxrc1GZaoiVpTbt26BjbUVmJiYls28W1iYcxNDcygu\/pvl5WGQohyOjoaJEyfC8eN\/kgXgdFwcBAT4w8WLl8iiPGJFwXWsSZMmQWJSElkAYo4cAX9\/f7hxQ3iOIsVgmy9tgKJ06dJFVPOlDr4+PvC1UZRycBjt6+sLd+7K7m8o06eog\/FJqUJxcTG05kZsV9IzyFKOURTxaLz5srW1hfz7sjuJRlHEUyZKfn4+XL9+XXT6+2\/JSCgjI51rw79maSk32cPl89lz5pTZ9u3bzz6nSBTcp+crRyiVlJTQT1bGoETBFdi9e\/eKTvfv32c\/pylRzp8\/z1uOUHossOhobL54MDZf6mPs6HUQjYpiHBJrBo03X0IYRRGPURQdxCiKDiIjCjpIJCYmwq1bt8giobT0NcTHx7NVZFVQRhQcHqenp1OuHPy9bt6s\/HtVxWBFad2qJTg6OpFFwiczZ7Dl\/HSekZUYUBRckHwhMOmryID3+kODho0qOWKHffcdK7\/i6jUfBtt8eXt5Qb369cv2L65fv8YqZMHCRSyvCrgdbGNjA8W0EiCPQG7yieXl5OSy\/JPCQjAxqcWN7D5keXmM9\/WBZV98STn9hFeUpUuCWaVIN5ncBg0Cc4sWoipUiCxumNy0SVNO4BtkEWZ71DZWfkKiZE9lir8\/l6\/JNZ15LC+P3r2dISxsHeX0E15R9u\/bxyolI\/MqnDp5kl0fOPAL3VUNbIpwtn8h9SJZhElJTmZlRkf\/DllZd9l1iAh\/MWx60Y3pxMn\/kkU\/4RUlLe0Sq4iNmzaBXdeu0KdPX7qjHu+7uUHU9h2UE+ZBQQHUrFmTNUPDPT2gjWVbePnqFd0VBs+5tGvXDnJyJc2evsIrCjpONGvWFKysrJg4ly9foTvqMS8wEKZOm045YdBxrws3UpP6fB05EkN35PPHsWPcCK8L91SWkkU\/4RUFK8W1X19WITM\/mUVW9UlMiAc7O3vKyQePNmD5I0aMJItipk+bBv5K+IjpKryiIE7du0ODBg3hsRoeLHx05YbFv\/x6kHLCjB09mokiZmCAvHjxHCwt20BKylmyVB87d+zghuY+MGnSZDh4UPhvLSoqgo0bN3J9d2WneV5RDh36jVXI5i0\/kEVzbNsaCZ07deaeRjLwcO7sWVb+Z5\/PJ4tiFi5YAEPdh1GuekCHxRHDPdnv7u7uDt26dWPXi4OX0CcqM4a+eN9\/v4EsEiqJcuLP42BtbS35T4d5kFXzDBo4EAIDgyhXDptgcn0Jlm\/fzUHURBNJvXAeLCws4MYNcU+Vttiwfj373bdU+DLjRBhtd+9mkUXCmm9CmB3T1q3byCqhkijJSUkwYcIEWLBgoVYPbT588ABsu9rCmjWhZJFw4\/p1Vv6sWbMgL7\/8bIo88Ng2Dgiiow+Tpfpw7tWTeZVW5D73d+zfvx+ePSsii+SUGYoxefJk9u8PVbxPBfsUbVNw\/z6MHjWKzT9wc0wVjh49Cn379oXfRLq0apPi4iKoX68eeHmNhNA1a7gBjS1bVlq5ahV9QgIeiGrYsAH4B0yBzIx03RJFyiGuQgsKHlBOOWJjY9VypRUCj5RHhIeX+RlUTRFcM\/XmTeVOEVcsTE1MoH79+tCqVSuuHwmGKVOmsEr39h5FnwIYOmQwtGzVml1fOH+O3Y+s2nw9f\/6cedhnZWW99YTlPuHmRLjyzHdfUUJB0AuH757YhGVXPR+JoqxfHwErVqzgTdgx84nyzjs1wdS0Nty8VR4paRkd57h0KQ3WhYVBrVomkHn1KruH3QXe275jJ8tLqREVFQWenp7g4eHxf5nGjRsHT58+pepQHfyC4JPS\/70BZJGQlJjIKn51SAjUqV2bXdvb27NjgNLJsbm5Bfj4jqef4ERR99yJIVD1ScF1Or9\/T+YVERMeYiotla03R4du0KJlq0rDfVxlwIrHEdn8+fNhGjfBxcEMpiFDhrB7Ln36wBLuiZJS7X2KLoIi5ebm8jZ3mHIFNvo2fC8ZEi9fvpLlnz59wuIG1KlTl9dP7XJaGvv8T3t\/Znn0pcONPIMXJTr6EDta4cPNsMMjIrS6HY2tTgDbZqjBOvu6deuwIHC7du+hT1Qm7tQp9tlNm7ewfPi6dSxv0KIs50ZK+Edi5ImhQyVNxdCh7loPLXWKq+w13LB4PTdKu337DlllwYhKSVxn\/4CbtyHYtw0ZPNhwRcG5D4oweIg7WQBWr1rJbNLNM10jOSmRnQs1WFHwaYiM\/IEdaJWCq9Qoyp86Gq4wNTUVklNSql8UfGSlHvzKgJ2x9LEXS6+ePdgyCK7O6jLVKsquXT\/Cxx9\/zCaRyoKi4Mnl2bPnKOwjcJsYz2w2atwYrtLETZepNlEC584BNzc3NqNXh8WLFkHv3i7wl0DQhIcPH4Jrv37QzMwMrl4TF+2iuqkWUVatXAkO3RxYMGdNsGjhAhgwcCDlysnJyQYba2s2y34lYo9fV3jrouAhIwtzC8jO0Wx0uv6urrB06TLKAbwsKYHujo5Qp25diImJYUPPuLg4ljSxrKJN3roonh4eEPTpZ5TTHBiDGAN4SleN4+JOcZO3uszWqFEjdi1NcSIjKVUXMqJoy5cYuXvnDlhaWiqMx6WqL7HboIGwctVqdo3zFBQIEy5xVEyvXulZXGJt+RIj330bCgMHDqKcMKr6Em\/ZvAnef\/8DyukvvM2XNnyJkTGjR0FwcPlqqBCq+hLjdnKnjp30Jv6wELyiaMOXGHHkOt7Yo8coJ4yqvsQ4wupmb881f+LDresivKJow5cY4wS34IQVExhUVV9ipFfPnrCjyk6evsErijZ8idF9qGWLlvCAm8wpQlVfYgSbSIM8CqENX2IURWxkPFxCUcWXGMHzKQZ5aAgrRdO+xMocr0NU8SVGDPogqqZ9iZUVRVlfYikGK4o2fImVEUUVX2IpBieKur7EuMAYHBwM+fmSYDoVQVEURcZjn1HBl7giBhcZT11fYlzawLWmy1dkl0jEiKKKL3FVjOEKecARVjbNxCsiRhRNYFCiqBqELS\/vHhw+fJilAwcOsGHsho0by2xnz51jn1MkiuaCsBmQKKoGYUtJTgI\/Pz+WMHQuLpOP5kZOUlvYOsnx6Yz0dLmiaC4Im7H5kgGPZd\/Lk+0PjM2XeDQqCjZpuAqQzrO+ZRRFPBoVBY9VODs7wzWeCZ9RFPFoVBRcnkGvEtwoqwqKYgwtJQ6N9ylCGEURz1sVxdh8iYNXFJwDoBNbVc9DHIaq8vJlBEXBiaWYpRPsm7Ccqgea0Cb1VhHCYEXBTSY8X+FWwQnhs6Ag5p6zb78k+LOyYLyvjh07itpSRq8X3M8ZO9aHLAD\/mT4NGjRsCMeO\/UEWfsb7+hru658C58xmC4P4htGDv\/7CrhctWkx3lQffHdnBpgNkZorz5Z3MTUSxzIfc07Fl82Z2HRr6Ld0VBl1Ud\/64i3L6iaAoj7jmy8LcnPnpoifJhH9NpDuqgSMyO1s7uJCaShb54GlbfPevq6skYsOMGTPpjjBYBntt4ak4sugncjv6sLUSXyt8bbgmTj+JjfclJXjxIla+h4cnWeRTFu+LZ0FUnxAUBfdG+vXtwyplmMhKUYTYeF8IHj2zt7Nl5U+YIO4pNfh4X+5Dh4CJqSnXwU5nFRMTI\/9tpGIQG+8LR38uLr2hcZOm4O\/nx8pPSlb8ZmyDjfeF8eonT5rEKuIQBaExM2sGVtY2Gjm6oCjeF26UeY2QvKc4PiERvyFgamoCPXs5864USNGleF\/qIiPKAW7Ii3Gq1oWXvzN+547t4OTkVLY3og6K4n1tjYxkERmioraTBY8yh7ETvvIO\/ehCvC9NISOKvG+jvHvKIBTvC1GlfF2J96UpBDt6bVIW7yu0crwvVcB4X5Y6Eu9LU1SLKAh+66dOnSoTFU4ZcLfSy8sL4uP1+1XnlQH4H1s8eHcyttT7AAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"vertical-align: middle; width: 98px; height: 90px;\" \/>&nbsp; given that 100 &lt; (<i>x <\/i>+ <i>y<\/i>) &lt; 200? <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"19","CORRECT_ANSWER":"19","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu30":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>30 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>31<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">If <i>p<\/i>, <i>q<\/i>, <i>m <\/i>and <i>n <\/i>are non-zero integers, such that the roots of the equation x<sup>2<\/sup> + <i>mx <\/i>+ <i>n <\/i>= 0 are <i>p <\/i>and <i>q<\/i>, whereas the roots of the equation x<sup>2<\/sup> + <i>px <\/i>+ <i>q <\/i>are <i>m <\/i>and <i>n<\/i>, find the equation whose roots are (<i>q <\/i>+ <i>n<\/i>) and (<i>p <\/i>+ <i>m<\/i>). <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><em>x<\/em><sup>2<\/sup> &minus; 4 = 0 <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT2":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><em>x<\/em><sup>2<\/sup> &minus; 2<em>x<\/em> + 4 = 0 <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT3":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><em>x<\/em><sup>2<\/sup> + 4<em>x<\/em> &minus; 4 = 0 <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT4":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><em>x<\/em><sup>2<\/sup> + 2<em>x<\/em> &minus; 8 = 0 <\/font><\/span><\/p>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu31":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>30 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>31<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">A rice merchant sells two varieties of rice, A and B, the ratio of whose cost prices is 3 : 2. If he sells A at a 15% profit and B at a 10% loss, find the overall profit or loss made by the merchant by selling equal quantities of both the varieties. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>5% profit\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>7.5% profit\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>2.5% loss\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'>13% profit\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu32":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>32 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>33<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">Find the number of values of <i>x <\/i>which satisfy the equation 3<sup>2<\/sup><em><sup>x<\/sup><\/em> + 5<em><sup>x<\/sup> &ndash;<\/em> 106 = 0. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"1","CORRECT_ANSWER":"1","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu33":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>questions <\/i><i>32 <\/i><i>and <\/i><i>33<\/i><i>: <\/i>Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\">On an ascending escalator in a shopping mall, A and B take 18 seconds and 12 seconds respectively to walk up from the ground floor to the first floor. If A and B start simultaneously, in opposite directions, from the ground floor and the first floor respectively, they will meet after nine seconds, by when A would have taken 27 steps. Find the number of steps visible in the escalator. <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"72","CORRECT_ANSWER":"72","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu34":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><b>DIRECTIONS <\/b><i>for <\/i><i>question <\/i><i>34<\/i><i>: <\/i>Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\">If <i>a<\/i>, <i>b <\/i>and <i>c <\/i>are in geometric progression, with a common ratio of <i>r<\/i>, where <i>r&nbsp;<\/i><\/font><\/span>&ne;<span style=\"color: black; font-family: Arial;\">&nbsp;1, while <\/span><i style=\"color: black; font-family: Arial;\">a<\/i><span style=\"color: black; font-family: Arial;\">, 3b and 5c are in arithmetic progression, find the value of <\/span><i style=\"color: black; font-family: Arial;\">r<\/i><span style=\"color: black; font-family: Arial;\">.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAgCAYAAADEx4LTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAGzSURBVDhP1dRNSwJBGAfwNRD1Yq6UoUEFnsou9Q2yi\/gNhIp8CSE7ZHouqM7VpYJCvXiuqG5mt8osvOjVUCM1EV8QBS\/+250dhl5UOtYfHpx55oeus7PLoUeury7hdrvRarVoB+iKn5+fMKLTQa0epB0pX3ChkIfHswqO46BQKMDzWlSrNbr6DR\/s70Eul+Pk5BQupxMy2UBvnM+\/oVwuk7HL6SC\/0BN\/jsO+\/O\/w0uLC7\/GasN88z6NWq9NOH9xsNlGpVNDpdGinD+6Wv4LD4TCsVissFkvfEg1XKpWQyWSQzWb7lmj+4m6EggHhANlhs9lYuVZWyN0Uw7B4WyfGx8jhMRqNrGZmZ1GvS+eD4fdikUCv10c7P8Pww\/0dwcFgCLFYjFS73aarUhg+PjokWKPRQKlUkrFer0c0ekvFJ7zhXSdge3tHeH8UkEgkYJqahEqlQjr9QgzDjUYDyWSSzqTcRCLSF+zskjnD3ZJKpQh2OJxkzvC8eQ5Tpmk6k3JxfkZwQPjTYn5c8+bmForCNsbjj9AND8FgGGXP4ZfL8Pt90Gp5ARiETy3mzGbkcq90FfgApCGtqjUm6msAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAgCAYAAADEx4LTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHHSURBVDhP1ZRNSwJRGIWnUlwk1mgZunEhGfUPKnCbiS2qbUVlYF+7alviDyj7WBVUCzcGFVQrl1mi1qoEtxqkZmKGaAni6c71NliptKwDl5nznmeYmXfeOxxq6OL8DDabDfl8nlWAqvDt7Q061GooFC2sUtYXOB6PYWFhHhzHQSaTgeeVeHnJsPQb7NxYh1Qqxe7uHmasVjQ0NNaGY7FHpFIpej5jnaZ3qAlXanpq8t\/BE+Njv4cXSb95nkcm88oqdeBcLod0Oo1SqcQqdeBq+iuwy+WC2WyGyWSquwSGSyaTiEQiiEajdZfA\/MVuBPx+DFks0Ov16Ovvh9t9xJKyRNjn89EtpdFo4XA4SAcG6CBtb+8wogIeHRmmYTyRYBWgy2CAqq0db+\/v1IvwA2lPKBRirqwuQydayQ7\/AX8qm83C4\/FgbnYWzXI5jk9OWVIFDgT80Ol0kEokUKnacOn1sqQKXCgUUCwW8Uy+bF9vL5rIRXd39zQTYWHIhYGvlO\/6ir60c3OLehEeJK3q7u5hrizh5yjA+weH1IvwyvISDVbX7EiQ9gWDAajV7VAqVcQ\/UebLM9vtayRUQqvV0qPRaEQ4HGYp8AGOxbiPWrNZpwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAgCAYAAADEx4LTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAImSURBVDhPzZTLTxNRFManG5tIgNDUFJN2oy7UBBcVDC5wKRhqZLQJXUlwUyApD3FNxY2iCQZIYQUu8EW64OGjNN1p0zCpwU2nTRNIu4Bi\/4C+SOnn9MztpNOpxCVf8i3OOb\/ce+6TQ5XyuRw8Hg+cTid5cWkJheNjVgVU8L2ebuj1ejgcDrKO49Df72DVKnja7QYnFT+vrbEM8HZ2lnLz8wsUK\/Dm5gZcLheKxSLLAPt7ewQPDY9QrGqjVm9ezxC8tfWF4n\/CPp+PwAd9PEqlEuXqwhvr6wTe7e5BoVBg2TrwzKuXBLpGR3FyIo9YkQoeGR6CTqfDh4+fWEYtBX6\/ukoj9vE8QqEQAoEA\/H4\/ORqNEqPA7TetBNfz4OATYhQ4FotBFEVEIhGNU6kUMZoFnqazAnu9XtjtdvDSlp3mMsMlEgmEw+H\/8lncjfJpDQw8htVqhc1mw\/a2n1VkKfDv3V00NTVKbsbY2Dhud3bSvVheXmFEFfzoIU\/FZDLJMsCVy5dgar2IPHsAChyPxyEIAotkXb92FY3STDnpPylLs8BMJoNgMIhnk5M439CgeggaWBB2YLFYqCWj8QJ2qmbTwPl8DtlsFoeHB7jV0Y5z0g8lijUvpaxKbxUFf\/6gGebman6k+7ZetLXdYJGs79++ytu38o5iBX46MUGF59MvkE6n8Uu6OK0mE1paDDg6+kOMqg331BQMBgPMZrO0OCO6uu4o\/QLAX7NKkbyzTYuPAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'> <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAfCAYAAAAx6zerAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAF5SURBVDhP1dRPSwJBGAbwFYRst5N20uxi9gkMJMGDB0+aZl38ExW6F8nPYTetm9pFWtdSsJP4Ecy+gOgpTxoYpIGou\/Dkjgtl7JpHe+CF2Xd+sywzy1BQyVOlgkQiAUEQ5Q6giJ\/rdRgMBphMO3JnngX81uuBjcVAURQYhoHZvIvxeCLP\/sIPPA+9Xo\/HUgmXF+ezBVvqePAxwGg0IuOzSBj0Jq2OfyYSDoGmmX+FA8d+soUr4etkEh6PF9OpIHeWYKWsC+50OqjVaqhWq0tLMlS5XAbLsohGo0tLMuu+G6IootlsYjJZ4bhPTwLk32i123JHBadTKQL\/xC+NBkGOQwc0Gg1aLRX8ORxie3YFxONXKHD38zer4SOvB0ajiYxz2Yw6vr1JY0Onw+vs+KXkMnPc7fbIsxSCRUEgE1qtFm63G06nE3sWC+nZbAfgCvwiDgWD8Pt8cLlcpPatVoLtdjv4YvEbK+Uum1X+DKVw+Ty57\/r9d7kDfAFPdZRvkRYUBAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"}}